字幕来源：可乐MK
加利福利亚 洛杉矶 1998年
男孩们 快走
Boys, let's go.
快点 跟紧点
Come on, tighten up.
排成一行
Single file, gentlemen.
走在走廊中央
Center of the hall.
单元一有状况
Condition unit one!
单元一有状况 收到
Condition unit one, copy that.
坐地上 举起双手 快
On the ground. Show me hands, let's go.
双手
Hands!
蓝色代号 有人打架
Code blue! Fight in progress!
来嘛 让我们打啊 放开他吧
Come on, let's fight, man! Let him go!
起码让我穿回我的鞋啊
At least let me get my shoes.
- 玛丽 安妮 - 你好
-Mary Anne. - Hello.
谢谢
Thank you.
阿多尼斯今天打架了…
Adonis got into a fight today…
而他被禁闭了
and he's in holding.
如果你想见他我们就要上去那里了
If you wanna see him, we're gonna have to go up there.
他是个好孩子 他只是…
He's a good kid, he just…
打架
fights.
经常性
All the time.
- 约翰逊 - 是的
-Johnson? - Yeah.
- 这边 - 谢谢
-Right this way. - Thanks.
约翰逊 有访客
Johnson, got a visitor.
阿多尼斯
Adonis.
进来吧
Come on in.
我想你见见…
I'd like you to meet Mrs…
我们可以单独聊一下吗 拜托了
Could we have a moment, please?
当然
Sure.
我就在外面等
I'll be right outside.
为什么你打架
Why were you fighting?
我不会再去另一个儿童之家
I'm not going to another group home.
我不是儿童之家的人
I'm not from a group home.
- 你是社工 - 不
-You a social worker? - No.
我不是社工
I am not a social worker.
那死黑鬼说了些我妈妈的事所以我揍他
Nigga said something about my ma so I beat his ass.
我对你母亲的事很遗憾
I'm sorry about your mother.
我知道失去至亲是什么感觉
I know what it's like to lose someone.
当你父亲死的时候我很生气
When your father died, I was angry for so long.
我伤害自己 不管家人
I hurt myself, pushed family away.
我没有父亲
I don't have no father.
- 你说什么 - 我说我没有父亲
-What did you say? - I said I don't have no father.
才不是
That's not true.
他在你出生前离世了 但你是有父亲的
He passed before you were born, but you had a father.
你认识他
You knew him?
他曾经是我的丈夫
He was my husband.
阿多尼斯 我很乐意…
Adonis, I would like it very much…
你来跟我一起生活
if you would come and stay with me.
你想这样吗
Do you think you'd wanna do that?
他叫什么名字
What was his name?
奎迪
墨西哥 蒂华纳 2015年
- 詹姆士 - 多 坐吧
-Hey, James. - Don, sit down.
你拿着什么
What you got there?
你在开玩笑 对吧
You're joking, right?
你要升职了而你要辞职
You get a promotion and you're quitting?
听着 只是这职位不适合我
Look, this career just ain't for me.
你要去做什么
What are you gonna do?
老兄 谢谢一直以来的照顾
Hey, man, thanks for everything.
只是想跟你谈谈我的工作
Just wanna talk to you about my job.
你看到你的新办公室了
You see your new office?
是的 但…
Yeah. But…
那看起来怎么样
Well, what's it like?
这升职可是很难得的机会
This is a big deal, this promotion.
他们给你请了助理吗
Did they hire your assistant?
- 谢谢 - 真为你自豪
-Thank you. - Very proud of you.
打他 打他的身体
Take it to him. Take it to the body.
就这样
There you go!
注意时间 宝贝
Make your time count, baby.
你知道怎么应对 就这样
You know what's coming up. There you go.
看看吧
Check it out.
- 你来这里干什么 - 打了15场全胜
-What you doing here, man? - 15 and 0, 15 knockouts.
在蒂华纳 不 兄弟
In Tijuana? No, bro.
那是酒吧打架而已
That's barroom brawling.
不管怎么样我都要打
Well, I'm all in anyway.
所以我觉得我们在外地开始只是取得我们的势头…
So I figure we start out local, just to get our momentum going…
然后我们就可以去我们想去的地方
then we can move wherever we wanna move.
- 「我们」 - 我是觉得…
-"We"? - I was figuring…
阿多尼斯 这些人来这里是为了生存
Adonis, these boys come in here, this how they survive.
他们得为了生命而战斗
They gotta fight for life.
杀人或被杀 人死在那里
Kill or be killed. People die in there.
你爸爸死在擂台上 这不是开玩笑
Your daddy died in the ring. This ain't no joke.
我不认识他 跟我没任何关系
I don't know him. Ain't got nothing to do with me.
- 好吧 你现在很厉害了 - 是的
-Okay, you real tough now. - Yup.
不 我不会训练你的
Nah, I ain't training you.
我不会训练你 没有人会训练你的
You know I ain't training you. Nobody training you.
我会确保没人训练你的
I'm gonna make sure about that.
我们准备在特尔斐拳击馆拿冠军
We making champs in the Delphi Gym!
我们不是在跳舞唱歌 我们在战斗
We not dancing! We not singing! We fighting!
你每天都在奋斗 你是为了某些东西而战
You struggle every day, you fight for something.
你就对了
You damn right!
听好了
Hey, listen up!
阿多尼斯
Adonis.
这些是我在这里的钥匙
These the keys to my 'Stang right here.
阿多尼斯 从擂台下来
Adonis, get out the ring!
你所要做的是直接击中头部…
All you gotta do is land one clean head shot…
我要它来干什么
What I gotta put up for it?
怕死吗 你是专业选手 对吧
Put up your hands. You a pro, right?
不…
No, no, no.
你会被打到屁滚尿流的
You gonna get the shit knocked out of you.
你不需要跟我证明些什么
You ain't gotta prove nothing to me.
最好听你家人的话吧 孩子
Better listen to your family, boy.
我的天
Oh, my God.
起码戴上你的头盔啊
At least put on your head gear.
不戴头盔
No head gear?
很好
It's good.
杀手 是吧
Killer, right?
他是个杀手 对吧 李 杜克
He a killer, right, Lil Duke?
当我在儿童之家时你在哪
Where were you at when I was iin group homes?
你错过一顿饭了吗 不
You miss a meal? Nah!
这里哪个是你下一个杀手
Which one of your killers in here next?
你选吧 你选谁是下一个
You pick him! You pick who's next!
我来
I'm next.
我只需要一个回合 兄弟
Hey, I just need one round, bro.
好吧 你要热身吗
All right, you wanna warm up?
我不需要热身 拿我的东西来
I don't need no warm-up. Get my stuff.
我看到你戴上你的头盔了 干得好
I see you got your head gear on. Good job.
不
No.
别跑啊
Don't run.
跟你说了我会赢的 我早跟你说了
Told you I'd win.I told you.
我早跟你说了 你就是不听
I tried to tell you something, bro. You don't wanna listen.
你就是不想听
You don't wanna listen.
你就是想挨苦头 是吧
You wanna learn things the hard way, huh?
- 最近怎么样了 - 很好
-How you doing? - Doing good.
我只是回家想跟你谈谈
I just came home, I wanted to talk to you.
- 是吗 - 我辞职了
-Yeah? - I quit my job.
你从哪里受的伤 墨西哥
Where did you get this? Mexico?
不是很严重
It's not that bad.
「不是很严重」
"It's not that bad."
我应该亲自揍你的
I ought to knock you out myself.
你知道有多少次我要扶你父亲上这楼梯…
You know how many times I had to carry your father up these stairs…
- 因为他走不动 - 知道
-because he couldn't walk? - Yes.
有多少次我帮他擦屁股因为双手都动不了
How many times I had to wipe his ass because he couldn't use his hands?
你是想那样吗 不
Is that what you want? No.
你想要脑损伤 你就是想
You want brain damage. Yeah, you do.
你想要很严重的脑损伤 你连说话都不能
You want to be so brain-damaged, you can't form a sentence.
我做任何事都有受伤的可能性的
I can get hurt doing anything.
阿波罗不是受伤 是被杀了 那些人是被杀
Apollo didn't get hurt, got killed! People get killed!
我收养你不是为了回到从前
I didn't take you in for you to go backwards.
你值得拥有比这更好的
You're better than this.
我很快就会走
I'm leaving soon.
我现在要做职业选手了
I'm gonna be fighting full-time now.
所以我想当面告诉你
So I wanted to tell you face-to-face.
你是你父亲的儿子…
You are your father's son…
你是他的一部分
and you're part of him.
但不代表你一定要成为他那样
But it doesn't mean you have to be him.
我会打电话给你的
I'm gonna call you.
听着 你要上擂台…
Listen, you want to be in somebody's ring…
你就别打电话给我了
you don't have to call me.
好了 茄子
All right, smile!
你好吗
How you doing?
这是在首战的第十回合拍的 对吧
This was taken from the 10th round of the first fight, right?
没错
Good call.
你怎么知道的
How'd you know that?
我听说完场后你和阿波罗之间…
I heard about a third fight between you and Apollo…
有一场第三战
behind closed doors.
是真的吗
That true?
你哪里听说的
How'd you hear about that?
谁赢了
Who won?
这算是个秘密 你之前说你叫什么名
Its kind of a secret. What'd you say your name was?
唐尼
Donnie.
女孩说你想谈些事
The girl said you wanted to talk about something.
是的 我想跟你谈谈训练我的事
Yeah, I want to talk to you about training me.
训练你
Training you.
我不再训练人了 很抱歉
I don't do that stuff no more. Sorry about that.
听着 现在很晚了 所以我要关门了
Listen, it's getting kind of late, kid. So I'm gonna dose up.
他有多厉害
How good was he?
谁 阿波罗 他很厉害
Who? Apollo? Yeah, he was great.
他是个完美的拳击手 没有人更甚
He's a perfect fighter. Ain't nobody ever better.
那么你是怎么打倒他的
So how'd you beat him?
是时间打倒了他
Time beat him.
时间带走所有人 是无敌的
Time takes everybody out, it's undefeated.
不管怎么样 我要关门了
Anyway, I gotta lock up.
当米奇死的时候他来跟你谈过 对吧
When Mickey died, he came and talked to you, right?
叫你别放弃
Talked you out of quitting?
带你去洛杉矶 训练你…
Took you to L.A., trained you…
让你重新振作
brought you back.
- 你怎么知道这些事的 - 你觉得呢
-How do you know all this? - How do you think?
- 你是什么人 亲戚吗 - 他是我父亲
-What are you, like a cousin? - He's my father.
不 才不是 我不相信你
No, he isn't. I don't believe you.
打给玛丽 安妮啊
Call Mary Anne.
玛丽 安妮 他的妻子
Mary Anne. His wife.
家庭电话没有变
The house number still works.
是哦 你自从葬礼后就没跟她谈过了
Oh, that's right. You haven't talked to her since the funeral.
虽然她说你说了一段很好的演讲
She said you gave a nice speech, though.
是啊
Yeah.
很好的演讲
Nice speech.
我要你训练我
I want you to train me.
我需要一个可靠的人而还有哪个更好的
I need somebody solid and who else better to go to?
这是你欠我的
You at least owe me that.
我看你说话你是个文化人
I can tell the way you talk, you been to school.
所以我以为你挺聪明的
So I figure you got some brains.
为什么你要选择一个拳击手的人生…
Why would you want to pick a fighter's life…
而当你没这个必要
when you don't have to?
如果阿波罗还活着他也会这么跟你说
If Apollo was around, he would tell you that, too.
但他不在了
Well he ain't around.
我一生都在打拼 我没有选择
I been fighting my whole life. I ain't got a choice.
这总是关于一个选择
It's always about a choice.
我以前在擂台上
I was in the ring.
我看到是什么下场 那场比赛应该停止的
I saw how it went down. That fight should've been stopped.
我应该阻止它
I should have stopped it.
也许他想像一个拳击手的死去
Maybe he wanted to go out like a fighter.
也许你做的完全是他所想的
Maybe, you did exactly what he wanted.
我觉得他了宁愿在这里跟你聊天
I think he'd rather be here, talking with you.
你们很相似
There is a resemblance.
我一般都在这里…
I'm usually here all the time…
所以如果你在附近想过来…
so if you're ever in the neighborhood, come by…
如果你需要什么
if you need something.
我明天会在米奇的拳击馆
I'll be at Mickey's Gym tomorrow.
我不去那里的 我没去那里很久了
I don't go there.I haven't been there in a long time.
既然我们像家人一样…
Since we're pretty much like family…
第三场比赛谁赢了
who won the third fight?
他赢了
He did.
在拳击里…
In boxing…
拳击手的起点是…
fighters' origins can endure as the most…
他们形象最神圣的要素…
sacred element of their identity…
一个选择可以永远改变他们的人生
shaping choices that can change their lives forever.
「漂亮」 瑞奇康兰是英格兰利物浦出身
"Pretty" Ricky Conlan is a faithful son of Liverpool, England…
是一个人们在传说中的英雄…
a place where people find hope…
寻找希望的地方
in the tales of their heroes.
但对于世界上不败最强的同等级重量拳击手来讲…
But for the undefeated best pound-for-pound boxer in the world…
未来是充满不确定性的…
the future is filled with uncertainty…
随着一个监禁七年的判决逼近
with a seven-year prison sentence looming.
我不打算在监房里浪费我的全盛时期
I didn't plan on spending me prime years in a prison cell.
我讨厌让我的家人失望
I hate letting me family down.
现在在家等着他的最后比赛会是什么…
Now what could be his final bout awaits him at home…
在他城市里其中一座最神圣的体育馆
in one of his city's most hallowed sporting temples.
这里 他会迎接一位同样从没被击败过的对手…
Here, he'll welcome an opponent who's also never been beaten…
一个以他的方式从加利福利亚街头…
and who's boxed his way from California streets…
打到成为美国巨星
to American stardom.
从著名的特尔斐拳击学院出来…
Fighting out of the famed Delphi Boxing Academy…
有一个被过去偶像的父亲指导的教练…
with a trainer whose father guided icons of the past…
丹尼「特技演员」 惠勒相信他是这项运动的未来
Danny "Stuntman" Wheeler believes he's the sport's future.
康兰要离开很久 现在轮到我了
Conlan's going away for a long time. Now it's my turn.
我从来没输过
I've never lost.
我甚至从来没被击倒过而这也不会改变
I've never even been knocked down, and that's not gonna change.
一个在黑暗和非凡窘况中的冠军
A champion in a dark and extraordinary predicament.
一个对英雄送别很冷漠的挑战者
A challenger uninterested in a hero's send-off.
这是7月24日 康兰和惠勒大战
This is 24/7. Conlan/Wheeler.
揍死这家伙
Kick this dude ass.
一点也不尊重人
No respect, man.
我是唐尼
I'm Donnie.
干嘛
Yeah?
我刚搬到楼上
And I just moved in upstairs.
好吧 你想干什么 唐尼 很晚了
Okay. What do you want, Donnie? It's late.
我听到你的音乐
I can hear your music.
是吗 我不知道那么大声
Yeah? I didn't know it was that loud.
是很大声 好吧 我要早起出去
Well, it is, all right? I gotta wake up early and work out.
知道了
Got you.
你要早起健身
You gotta wake up early and do your jawns.
保持你的身材
Keep your body tight.
我会把音乐调小声 你不会听到的
I'll turn my music down. You won't hear a peep.
谢谢…
Thanks…
接回去
Snap it back!
呼吸 利奥 呼吸
Breathe, Leo, breathe.
好样的
Good boy.
- 有什么帮到你 - 想报名
-Can I help you? - Looking to sign up.
- 你从哪里来的 - 洛杉矶
-Where you from? - L.A.
好莱坞
Hollywood!
哪间拳击馆的 我认识全部同行
Which gym? I know all those guys.
没加入过 我是自学成才的
Don't have one. I'm more self-taught.
自学成才
Self-taught?
你认识巴尔博亚
You know Balboa?
是的 我们一起长大的
Yes, we grew up together.
大多数会员只是自己训练
Most members just work themselves out.
一个月额外给二十美元我可以给你操练 当我有空指导你
For an extra $20 a month, I can give you drills, check in on you when I can.
可以
Yeah, that works.
双刺拳
Double jab.
移动你的头
Move your head, babe.
拳击粉丝们已经等了很多年…
Boxing fans have been waiting years…
「漂亮」 瑞奇 康兰和丹尼 惠勒之间的超级大战
for the Superfight between "Pretty" Ricky Conlan and Danny Wheeler.
但我们想他们等不及再来的24小时了
But we guess the fighters couldn't wait another 24 hours.
在记者会后康兰给了惠勒一拳
Conlan punched Wheeler after words were exchanged during the face-off.
惠勒下巴受伤…
Wheeler suffered a broken jaw…
而且宣布计划起诉康兰和世界拳击理事会
and has already announced plans to sue Conlan and the WBC.
大叔
Hey, Unc!
Unc!
你好吗
How you doing?
你刚叫我「大叔」吗
Did you call me "Unc"?
是的 或OG
Yeah, it was either that or O.G.
什么是「OG」
What's an "O.G."?
老家伙
Old-ass gangster.
「大叔」 就好了
"Unc" is good.
- 我可以搬 - 没关系
-I can do that. - It's all good.
那么你为什么过来 你饿了吗
So why'd you come by? You hungry?
不 我刚练完拳 想过来看看
No, I just wrapped up at the gym. Figured I'd stop by.
好吧
Okay.
- 可以问你个问题 - 当然 这些我都可以搬
-Can I ask you a question. - Sure. I can do all this.
我可以做些什么训练来提高我的手速
What are some drills I can do to get my hand speed up?
那里的有些人我想他们可以帮到你
Some guys up there, I bet they can help you.
哪里有个叫彼得的家伙 他是个不错的教练
There's a guy there named Pete. He's a pretty good trainer.
但他大部分时间都跟他的拳手一起
Yeah, but he's with his fighter most of the time.
我基本上只是自己训练
I mostly just train myself.
他们知道你是奎迪的后代吗
They know you're a Creed?
我不用那一套 我要自己打出名堂
I don't go by that. I'm trying to make it on my own.
约翰逊的大名
Name's Johnson.
- 谁是约翰逊 - 我妈的名字
-Who's Johnson? - Mom's name.
另外让生活更轻松
Plus, just makes life easier.
再加上 如果你训练我…
Plus, if you train me…
周围没人认识我 我们可以秘密进行
nobody around knows me. We could fly under the radar.
- 他们永远都不会知道 - 好吧
-They'd never know. - Yeah.
我之前就跟你说了…
I told you before…
我只是不想做 孩子
I just don't wanna do it, kid.
没关系 但也许你可以给我些训练
Tha's cool, but maybe you could just give me some drills.
- 训练 - 是的 一些我可以自己做的训练
-Drills? - Yeah, things I could do on my own.
你就是不罢休 是吧 你就像一只啄木鸟
You don't stop, do you? You're like a woodpecker.
天啊
My God.
好吧 我有些训练
All right. I got a few.
- 但到此为止 好吧 - 没问题
-But that's it. Okay? - Of course.
跳绳五个回合
Five rounds of jumping rope.
每个沙包打三回合…
Three rounds on each of the bags…
当你打重的沙包…
When you get to the heavy bag…
不要只顾着挥动你的双手 因为你会受伤的
just don't keep throwing your hands because you can hurt them.
同时也要用你的双脚 好吧
It's also about using your legs, all right?
然后五个回合…
And then five rounds of…
拳击…
shadow…
土下面山
O-W.
- 有一个「山」 训练 - 训练 对
-There's a "W". Boxing. - Boxing, yeah.
就这样
And that's it.
- 好了吗 - 好的
-All right? - Yeah.
好了 给你
Okay, here you go.
这太好了
That is perfect.
祝你幸运
Good luck with that.
拍好了 先拿着
All right, got it. Hold that real quick.
再见了
All right, man.
等等 你不要这个吗
Wait, don't you want this?
我这里有了
I got it right here.
万一你丢了那玩意或它坏了
What if you lose that thing or it breaks?
已经传上云端了
It's already up in the cloud.
什么云
What cloud? What cloud?
妈妈 是我
Hey, Ma, it's me.
我只是打来让你知道我很好…
I was just calling to let you know I'm doing good…
而且我租了公寓
and I got an apartment.
这没什么但我会让它变得更好
It ain't much but I'm trying to make it into something.
我很想念你
I miss you.
我想听你的近况…
I wanna hear from you…
所以你有空就回我电话吧 就这样
so call me back when you get a chance. All right.
干嘛 很吵吗
What, it's too loud?
不 我只是听到你在这下面工作
No, I just heard you down here working.
看看你想不想休息一下
Figured you'd wanna take a break.
也许吃点东西
Maybe get some food?
- 你是从里来的 唐尼 - 我从洛杉矶来的
-Where you from, Donnie? - I'm from L.A.
所以你在洛杉矶是这样跟女性搭讪的
So is this how y'all ask females out in L.A.?
只是看看你肚子饿不饿
Just wanted to know if you were hungry.
- 不是约会 - 好吧
-Not a date. - Right.
随便吧 没关系
You know what? It's all good.
没关系
It's okay.
等等
Hey, yo.
我饿了
I am hungry.
我只有一个小时 你知道你想去哪吗
I only have an hour. Do you know where you wanna go?
我是想你告诉我的 你是费城的人 对吧
I was hoping you could tell me. You're from Philly, right?
好吧
Okay.
祝你幸运
Good luck, man.
- 那么我们在哪 - 费城北部
-So where are we? - North Philly.
那么这是麦斯
So this is Max's.
巨星 最近好吗
Hey, superstar! What's going on?
我很好 谢谢 你好吗
I'm well, thanks. How you doing?
- 你总是一如既往的漂亮 - 谢谢
-You looking wonderful as always. - Thank you.
那里的朋友 你好吗
How you doing there, my friend?
这是我的邻居和他是个西海岸人
This my neighbor and he's a West Coast boy.
以前从没吃过碎牛肉
Ain't never had a steak before.
听着 我会对待你像他是我的邻居一样
Listen, I'm gonna treat him like he was my neighbor.
这就是我们对你有多好
That's how good we gonna take care of you.
- 你要腌菜吗 - 不
-You like pickles? - Nah.
好的 蛋黄酱
Okay, mayonnaise.
加点辣椒 各种都要
Put some peppers on that jawn, both kinds.
番茄酱 加倍奶酪
Ketchup, extra cheese.
- 多少钱 - 9 95美元
-How much I owe you? - $9.95.
不 让我给吧
No, let me get these.
没关系 是我叫你出来的 对吧
That's cool. I asked you out, right?
但你说这不是约会
You said it wasn't a date, though.
这不是
It's not.
- 我们在哪里吃 - 里面
-Where we eating at? - Right there.
那么我在那里听你说这「玩意」 那「玩意」
So I heard you back there, "jawn" this, "jawn" that.
- 什么是「玩意」 - 这是个名词
-What's a "jawn"? - It's a noun.
看 这些是玩意
See, these is jawns.
这是一个玩意
This is a jawn.
我们坐的这餐厅是一间玩意 你是一个玩意
This restaurant we're sitting in is a jawn. You're a jawn.
你有玩意吗
You got a jawn?
- 就是男朋友 - 没有
-Like, a dude? - No.
我现在有太多事情了
I got too much going on right now.
- 演出什么的 - 是的
-Shows and stuff? - Yeah.
我下个月要去电厂音乐会
I'm opening Electric Factory next month.
- 那是什么 - 是这里很大的一个馆
-What's that? - It's a big venue out here.
很多人都是从那开始的 吉尔 传奇乐队 根乐队
A lot of people got their start. Jill, Legend, the Roots.
不赖啊
That's wassup.
我可以问你些私人的问题吗
Can I ask you something personal?
我有慢性听力受损
I got progressive hearing loss.
我去年开始戴这些
Just started wearing these this past year.
但我只会在很嘈杂的地方需要他们
But I only need them in places with a lot of background noise.
目前
For now.
这是慢性的 所以最后…
So it's progressive, so eventually…
是的
Yeah.
没错
我只是在给它做准备
I'm just getting ready for it.
就像习惯这些 我在学手语什么的
Like I'm getting used to these, I'm learning sign language and stuff.
但我真的只能记住粗口
But I really can only remember bad words.
一些没什么用的 就像…
Ones that aren't that useful like…
这是什么
The fuck's that?
你看不出来吗 这是瞎 目字 这是…
You cant tell? This is the bull, the horns, this is…
对 这是瞎扯
Yeah, this is bullshit.
这是你最爱说的话
That's your favorite?
我看你不太像个拳手
You don't really seem like a boxer to me.
你身材很好还有很多像 但…
You're in shape and all but…
我也说不清 不像大部分拳手…
I don't know. Aren't most boxers like…
- 像什么 - 像小混混
-Like what? - Like street.
我不是说你是个正直的人什么的…
I'm not saying you're a square or anything…
但我只是很好奇是什么让你想打拳击
but I'm just curious, what made you wanna fight?
我老爸是一个拳手
My pop was a fighter.
好吧 这说得过去
Right. That makes sense.
他是职业拳手吗
Did he fight pro?
差不多吧
Something like that.
他训练你吗
Does he train you?
我老爸在我出生前就死了
My pop died before I was born.
听到这我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
那么是什么让你想唱歌
So what made you wanna sing?
这让我感到有活力
It makes me feel alive.
你下一场演出在哪
Where's your next show?
你看到我的那个地方 约翰尼 布伦达
That place that you saw me at, Johnny Brenda's.
我在那驻场 所以我们周五演出
I got a residency there so we're back on Friday.
我可以来吗
Can I roll with you?
我想来 支持下你
I wanna show up, you know. Show some love.
我考虑下吧
Let me think on it.
好吧
Okay.
来了 保利
Here we go, Paulie.
生日快乐 老朋友
Happy birthday, my friend.
我没忘记你
I didn't forget ya.
你的最爱
Your favorite.
想你了 兄弟
Miss ya, pal.
艾德里安 我亲爱的
Yo, Adrian, my darling.
精英中的精英
The best of the best.
我跟你说 艾德里安 天啊
I'll tell you, Adrian, God.
走上来这小山是越来越难了 这意味着什么
It's getting harder to walk up this hill. What does that mean?
不管则么样今天是个好日子 没烦恼的好日子
Anyway, it's a good day today. It's a good day, got no problems.
账单都付清了
Bills are paid.
唯一的是有时候晚上很难睡觉 我的背
Only thing is, it's tough to sleep at night sometimes. My back.
不管你怎么做都一样痛
No matter what you do, it catches up to you.
不管怎么样我们看看今天世界有什么新闻吧
Anyway, shall we see what's new in the world today?
- 洛奇 - 你好吗
-Hey, Rocky! - Hey, how you doing?
- 很高兴见到你 - 你好吗
-Good to see you. - How you doing?
洛奇 很久没见了 兄弟
Hey, Rock! Long time no see, brother.
- 还在这啊 很高兴见到你 - 好
-Still here? Good to see you. - Yeah.
- 意大利种马回来了 - 你好吗
-Hey, the Italian Stallion's back. - How you doing?
- 大家像这在里开派对啊 - 是的
-It's like a party here with everyone. - Yeah, right.
- 欢迎回来 很长一段时间了 - 是啊 非常感谢你
-Welcome back, man. It's been a while. - Yeah, thank you very much.
- 感觉怎么样 - 很好
-How do you feel? - Good.
- 什么 你要复出吗 - 不
-What, are you making a comeback? - No.
- 冠军 - 彼得 怎么了
-Hey, champ. - Hey, Pete. What's up?
- 不知道你要过来啊 - 我也不知道
-Didn't know you were coming by. - I didn't either.
我只是刚好在附近 你这里干得不错啊
I was just in the neighborhood. You've done nice here.
地方看起来不错 新装修一切都是新的
Place is looking good, new paint and everything.
- 非常好 非常漂亮 - 我尽我所能了
-Very good, very nice. - I do what I can.
- 还记得我的儿子利奥吗 - 当然
-Remember my son, Leo? - Of course I do.
自从你上次见他后大个头很多了
A lot bigger since you last seen him.
- 没错 非常大 - 洛奇…
-Yeah, very big. - Rocky…
他赢了17次0败
he's 17 and 0.
我们真的很顺利
Things are really opening up for us.
利奥
Leo!
洛奇 如果你想加入还是可以的
Rocky, option's still open if you wanna get involved.
做点小培训 来点激情
Little training, little motivation.
- 让我考虑下吧 - 当然
-Let me think about it. - Sure, sure.
- 你好吗 孩子 - 很荣幸见到你 冠军
-How you doing, kid? - It's an honor to meet you, champ.
也很高兴见到你 赢17次0败 非常好
Nice to meet you, too. 17 and 0, very good.
我本来应该跟瑞奇 康兰打的…
Yeah, I was supposed to fight under Ricky Conlan's card…
- 但被取消了 - 大叔
-but it got cancelled. - Hey, Unc!
大叔
Unc.
- 他在叫你吗 - 我想是吧
-He talking to you? - Yeah. I think so Yeah.
- 你来了啊 - 是的
-You made it. - Yeah.
只是顺路过来
Just walked by. Here I am.
- 你怎么认识好莱坞的 - 我们在餐厅认识的
-How you know Hollywood? - We met at the restaurant.
正是
That's it.
好吧 洛奇 好吧
Okay, Rock. Okay.
你需要什么就叫我
You need anything, you let me know.
- 好的 衷心的祝你幸运 孩子 - 谢谢
-Okay. Good luck, kid. Seriously. - Thanks.
17赢0败 这孩子很有前途 很彪悍
17 and 0. Kid's got a future. Tough.
我可以跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you a minute?
我不知道我来这里干什么
I don't even know what I'm doing here.
因为我的生活有其他打算…
because I got other plans for my life…
而这不是那的一部分
and this wasn't part of it.
你父亲很特别
Your father was special.
跟你说实话 我不知道你特不特别
Tell you the truth, I don't know if you're special.
只有在时机成熟你才会知道
Only you gonna know that when the time is right.
这不会在一夜之间达成
It ain't gonna come overnight.
你要不断的打 你要做这些训练…
You're gonna take a beating, you're gonna take this…
你会被击倒 你要爬起来…
you're gonna get knocked down, you're gonna get up…
然后如果你做对了你就会明白
and you're gonna see if you got the right thing.
但你必须努力
But, you gotta work hard.
我向天发誓 如果你不努力我就不干了
I swear to God, if you're not gonna do it, I'm out.
我击出的每一拳都是靠我自己的
Every punch I've ever thrown has been on my own.
没有人教我该怎么做
Nobody showed me how to do this.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
来吧 我们开始吧
Come on. Let's do this.
到我的办公室
Step into my office.
你认真的吗
You serious?
我认真的 这是老方法
I am serious. This is old school.
你应该有能力抓到这些鸟的其中一只
You should be able to grab one of these birds.
- 三十秒内 - 没错 做梦吧
-30 seconds? - Yeah, in your dreams.
快点 你这也叫快吗
Come on! You call that fast?
不 再来
No! Again.
我还以为你很快呢
I thought you were fast.
过来
Come here!
预测他们的动向
Get them legs moving!
努力点 跑快点
Little harder, little faster!
跟上节奏 继续跑
Keep up the pace! Keep going!
控制你的节奏然后慢慢加速
Control your tempo then build slowly.
快点
More.
加速
Build, build, build.
快
Go!
这铃声不是说放学了 唐尼 继续跳
That bell don't mean school's out, Donnie. Keep going.
这铃声代表累死你
That bell means hell.
快去抓那只鸡 这没多难
Just go get the chicken. It's not that big a deal.
过来啊 该死的
Come here! God damn it!
我的天
Oh, my God!
这很好 鸡都跑累了
That's pretty good. Chickens are slowing down.
好了 唐尼 摆好你的站姿
All right, Donnie, get into your stance.
做一个小目标 反向对着 好吧
Make a small target, turn sideways. Okay.
你看到这家伙凝视着你吗
You see this guy here staring back at you?
是的
Yeah.
这就是你最难对付的对手
That's your toughest opponent.
每次你上到擂台这就是你的对手
Every time you get into the ring, that's who you're going against.
在拳击里我是这样想而在生活里我也是这么想 好吧
I believe that in boxing and I do believe that in life, okay?
现在往下巴来一击刺拳
Now throw a jab in the jaw.
好了 一击到肚子
All right, one to the gut.
每次你对这家伙出拳 他会怎么做
Now, every time you punch this guy, what's he doing?
- 他会还我一击 - 没错
-He's throwing one back at me. - That's right.
所以你要么格挡它或者避开它 开始
So either you block it, slip it or get out of the way. Go.
我让你们慢慢练了
I'll leave you two alone for a while.
加油
Good luck.
怎么了 进来没问题
What's up? Is it cool?
可以
Yes.
这里挺香啊
Smells good in here.
我不知道拳手喝什么的 你喝茶吗
I don't even know what fighters drink. Do you drink tea?
茶很好 谢谢
Yeah, tea's good. Thank you.
没问题
Yeah.
- 那么这就是你的家 - 就这样
-So this is the house. - This is it.
你在做什么
What you working on?
这是你们从洛杉矶到费城的唐尼
This your boy Donnie From L.A. to Philly.
费城 奶酪碎牛肉的发源地
Philly, the home of the cheesesteaks.
我想来个奶酪碎牛肉
Oh, I want a cheesesteak.
我很饥饿 这歌就叫饥饿
I'm so hungry Hungry for the title.
我会吃个芝士蛋糕
I'll settle for a cheesecake.
芝士蛋糕 你做的蛋糕 你有的蛋糕
Cheesecake, the cake that you make The cake that you got.
- 伴奏呢 - 抱歉
-Where the beat go? - Sorry.
你听听
Hey, check you out.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
不错 非常好
I like that. Very good.
保持协调 继续
Keep that balance going. Way to go.
唐尼 起来 你得继续
Donnie, get up. You gotta keep moving.
这很困难但你得继续 你还不够彪悍
It's tough but you gotta do it. You get a "B" in tough.
这孩子状态不错啊 冠军
Kid's looking good, champ!
对 他越来越好了
Yeah, he's getting there.
好莱坞 你现在多重
Hey, Hollywood, what do you weigh right now?
我不知道 大概180磅吧
I don't know, probably like 180.
干嘛
Why?
如果你有兴趣 降到175磅我们来场比赛
Get down to a buck 75, we'll make something happen, if you're interested.
- 求之不得 我有兴趣 - 不
-Hell yeah, I'm interested. - No.
我负责说话 好吧 你负责打
I do the talking, okay? You do the fighting.
175磅 这是你儿子的体重
175? That's your boy's weight.
你好吗 利奥
How you doing, Leo?
- 怎么样 洛奇 - 好
-What's up, Rock? - Yeah.
他可以用一场比赛来保持知名度
He could use a fight to keep warm.
- 知名度 - 我不打算骗你
-Warm? - I'm not gonna lie to you.
人们会愿意来看你再出现在比赛 冠军
People will come out to see you in the corner again, champ.
我们会搞得像以前一样 全城都聚集在那
We'll make it like the old days. Get the whole city there.
给大家赚点钱
Make a few bucks for everybody.
不 我很明白
No, I understand that.
但我现在才刚开始训练这孩子
But I'm just getting used to this kid right now,
而他是越来越好…
and he's getting better every day…
但他还要练一段时间
but he's gonna take a while.
他很饥饿了
He's hungry.
你得满足他 你知道的
You gotta feed him every now and again. You know that.
谢谢 我很感谢 大师傅 我们没关系的
Thanks. I appreciate it, chef. We'll be okay. Thanks.
- 考虑下吧 - 我会考虑的
-Think about it. - I'll think about it.
洛奇 我们训练为的是什么
Rock, what we training for?
我们训练为的是什么
Yeah, what are we training for?
我们训练是为了赢 不被杀 你还没准备好
We're training to win, not get killed. You're not ready yet.
我可以减5磅 我可以就这样减5磅
I can lose five pounds. I can lose five pounds like that.
这没什么 很容易
It's nothing, It's easy.
打沙包
Hit the bag.
打吧
Come on.
这孩子就像一个彪悍的费城斗士
This kid's like a tough Philadelphia fighter.
我以前从没见过你比赛
I ain't never even seen you battle before.
但我一直有看他 而我很相信他跟不上我的滑板鞋
Yeah, but I've watching him, and I'm pretty sure he'd catch my fade.
- 什么是滑板鞋 - 我可以打倒他
-What's a fade? - I could take him out.
- 好吧 - 好了 听着
-Okay. - All right, listen.
我给你提个你无法拒绝的提议吧
Let me make you an offer you can't refuse.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
不 我认真的 这样 我们接受比赛
No, I'm serious, man. Look, we take the match.
好
Right.
我有六周时间训练 六周里我愿意付出任何代价
I got six weeks to get in shape. Six weeks, I'll do whatever it takes.
在六周后你觉得不行 就取消
At the end of the six weeks, you don't think it's right, call it off.
真的吗
Really?
这就是我来这的目的 对吗 我会全天候为了这目标
This is what I'm here for, all right? I'll go 24/7 with this shit.
事实上我们现在可以去拿我的东西
Matter of fact, we can go get my stuff right now.
- 拿东西干嘛 - 那么我可以搬进你的家啊
-For what? - So I can move into your spot.
开始训练营 老方法 还记得吗
Start training camp. Old school, remember?
不 很久没有人来过我家住了…
No, no one's been in my house in a long time…
而且我觉得你在那里会很不舒服
and I don't think you'd be comfortable there.
什么 你裸体满屋跑吗
What, you walk around naked?
没有
No.
那就没问题了
We're good then.
你最好也别裸体满屋跑
You better not walk around naked either.
不然你就死定了
That's for sure.
- 最后一件 - 对 这是全部行李了
-Last one? - Yeah, that's all of it.
你要搬走
You're moving?
对 今天太疯狂了 我还没来得及告诉你…
Yeah, today's been crazy. I didn't get a chance to tell you…
但我要去跟我叔叔住一段时间…
but I'm gonna be living with my uncle for a while,
为了接下来的比赛训练
training for the next fight.
那是你的叔叔
That's your uncle?
他是白人啊
He's white.
远亲
Yeah, a long time.
他会跟我住 当我们没有训练…
He's gonna be staying with me, and when we ain't training…
很欢迎你过来
you're welcome to come on over.
很好 谢谢 很高兴认识你
Cool, thank you. I'ts nice to meet you.
为什么你这样看着我
Why you giving me that look?
你什么时候会告诉我你叔叔是洛奇 巴尔博亚
When were you gonna tell me that your uncle's Rocky Balboa?
我会打电话给你的
I'm gonna call you.
好吧 我可不会等你电话的
All right, I'm not gonna hold my breath.
这个比安卡女孩看起来不错啊
That Bianca girl looks kind of nice.
你喜欢她
You like her?
她很不错 这间吗
Yeah, she cool. What, this one?
没错
Yeah.
女人会令你腿软 你知道我什么意思吗
Women weaken legs. You know what I mean?
我的脚没事 这曾经是谁的房间
My legs work just fine. Whose room was this?
- 是保利的房间 - 保利
-It's Paulie's room. - Paulie.
保利是我最好的朋友 虽然他不是很友好
Paulie was my best friend even though he wasn't so friendly.
他怎么了
What happened to him?
- 去世了 - 我很抱歉
-Passed away. - I'm sorry.
有点乱 我们会整理到很晚
Kind of a mess. We'll straighten it up later.
这会挺舒服的
It'll be comfortable.
这是张旧照片 这是你儿子
Oh, man, this is a dope pic! That's your boy?
这是我的孩子 罗伯特
Yeah, that's my kid, Robert.
- 你也训练他 - 我试过…
-Did you train him, too? - I tried…
但他就是不喜欢拳击 学不好
but he just didn't like fighting, didn't take to it.
他还在城里吗
He still around here?
不 他跟他女朋友搬到一个叫温哥华的地方
No, he moved to a place called Vancouver with his girlfriend.
我想他们在那过得很不错…
I think they're having a grand old time up there…
我现在有听到他的消息了…
and I hear from him now and then…
但以前他住在费城挺艰难的
but it was tough for him to live in Philadelphia.
我还有所有的事…洛奇之子
Me and all that stuff… Rocky's son.
他很开心 我为他感到很高兴
He's happy. I'm happy for him.
要不你收拾行李吧 当自己家就好了
Why don't you unpack, all right? Make yourself comfortable.
而我会去餐厅 我晚上回来
And I'm gonna go to the restaurant and I'll be back.
然后我们早上开始训练 好吧
Then we start first thing in the morning, all right?
没问题
You got it.
好吧 保利
All right, Paulie!
宝贝爱你哟
Baby love you.
是时候训练了 这就是你如何开始
Hey, it' s time to train. This is how you start.
让你充满活力
Get your engine going.
我要带你去的这个地方叫
I'm gonna take you to this place called.
前街拳馆 在费城北部
the Front Street Gym up in North Philly.
- 那很不错 - 好吧
-It's pretty good. - Okay.
你会在那里训练
You're gonna train there,
因为我不想你在对手…
because I don't want you to train in the same place…
同样的地方训练
as the guy that you're gonna be fighting, right?
这有道理
Yeah, that makes sense.
唐 别上车 我要你跟车跑
Don, don't get in. I want you to run alongside.
- 我有点老古董 对吧 - 没错
-I'm kinda antique, right? - Yeah.
那么我开车你尽量跟紧
So I'll drive and you try to keep up.
- 那有多近 - 够近的了
-How close is it? - It's close enough.
好吧
All right.
等等 让我先热身
Hey, wait! Let me warm up real quick.
你做到了
You made it. Hey.
我以为你说很近啊
I tought you said it was close.
没那么近 这里是弗兰克福 强者之地
Not that close. This is Frankford. Tough place.
你要成为费城斗士 这就是该去的地方
You wanna be a Philly fighter, is the place to go.
费城斗士 我认为他们是世界上最彪悍的人
Philly fighters, I think they're the toughest guys in the world.
在很多方面 也许是在水里 我也说不清…
In a lot of ways. Maybe it's in the water, I don't know…
但是个好地方
but great place though.
- 怎么那么多摩托车 - 这是费城特色
-What's up with all these bikes? - It's a Philly thing.
这些家伙玩特技和制造噪音
These guys are popping wheelies and making noise,
在街上跑来跑去
going up and down the street.
你骑摩托吗
Do you ride?
不 我有过一台哈雷但我摔下来了
No. I had a Harley once but I fell off,
所以我决定坐11路
so I decided to use my feet.
这孩子 斯皮诺 他有些特别
Now, this kid, Sporino, he got something special.
他没那么简单打倒所以你要下点功夫 明白我意思吗
He's no pushover, so you're gonna have to work, you know what I mean?
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
- 不错吧 - 很不错
-Not bad? - Not bad at all.
这里会训练得很好的 非常好的
Yeah. This'll get the job done. Really will.
看看这些家伙
Look at these guys!
这帮人都在这
Hey! The gang's all here!
唐尼 看看这 如果我没见过还以为这是水手呢
Donnie, look at this. This is a crew if I ever saw one.
- 将军 很高兴见到你 - 冠军 你好吗 兄弟
-Hey, Padman. Good to see you. - Hey, champ. How you doing, bro?
这家伙精通拳击手套 让会教你很多东西的
This guy is so good with the mitts, he's gonna teach you a lot of stuff.
他有很多知识
He's got a lot of knowledge.
而史迪奇 在费城里最好的伤口处理员
And Stitch, best cut man in Philadelphia.
希望我们不需要他吧
Hope we don't need him.
- 你好吗 - 欢迎到费城 兄弟
-What's going on? - Welcome to Philly, brother.
- 很荣幸 - 很高兴跟你一起训练
-Pleasure. - Glad to work wit you.
而这里的是埃尔维斯 格兰特
And over here is Elvis Grant.
他做出世界上最好的手套
He makes the best gloves in the world.
而作为我给你的礼物 先从右脚开始…
And as my present to you, starting out on the right foot…
- 很高兴认识你 - 也很高兴认识你
-Nice to meet you, man. - Nice to meet you too.
他会给你做一套手套让你的手不受那么多伤害…
He's gonna make you a pair of gloves so what your hands don't get so bad…
- 什么 我闻到到的是咖啡吗 - 没错 是咖啡
-What? Is that coffee I smell in there? - Yeah, that's coffee.
好了 你们互相认识下一吧
All right, you guys get to know each other.
- 阿米尔 - 好的 大叔
-Amir. - All right, Unc.
- 过来 - 我要喝点咖啡才行
-Come here. - Man, I could use some coffee.
让我向你介绍我的儿子
Let me introduce you to my son.
这是我的儿子 阿米尔 他将是你的练习对象
This is my son, Amir. That's the one you're gonna be sparring with.
- 阿米尔 - 你好 唐尼
-Amir. - What's up? Donnie.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
右手快点
Right hand fast.
来呀 来呀
Let it go, let it go.
后腿撑着
Push off that back foot.
快点 唐尼 再快点
Come on, Donnie, a little quicker.
唐尼 继续啊 不 学他做得那样
Come on, Donnie. Back it up. No, just like he's doing. Yeah.
- 我还不够快 - 就这样
-I can't pivot fast enough. - Yeah, just turn it.
这是你的力量
That's your power.
要快 出拳要快
Fast, pop it fast.
我尽我能力的快了
I'm popping as fast as I can.
我尽量像你跟我说那样后退撑着
I'm trying to push off my back foot like you told me.
唐尼 过来
Hey, Donnie. Come here.
但我来是跟你学的
I came out hew to work with you, though.
我就是这样教的 好吗 有些事我做不了
This is how I work, okay? There's some things I can't do.
我做不了体力活了 我不能再像这样拿着垫子
I can't do this anymore. I can never hold the pads like that.
但我看着你 我是在教你
But I'm looking at you. I m working with you.
我用头脑来教
I'm working with this.
听好了
Lighten it up.
我跟他们说真打了吗
Am I still taking them real shots?
缓着点
Slow it down. Hey, hey!
就这样
That's it. Hey, hey, hey!
这很简单
This easy work, Pop.
必须保持移动 就这样
Gotta keep moving. That's it.
时间到 铃声
Time! Bell! Bell!
给点力啊
Taking real shots thought!
你什么意思
What you mean?
- 到此为止 - 马上把手套脱了
-Cut it out! - Take those gloves off right now!
- 这是我的拳馆 - 把手套脱了
-This my gym! - Take the glove off right now!
你个渣渣滚回洛杉矶吧 你还是个垃圾 这是我的拳馆
Take your soft ass back to L.A.! You ain't ready yet! This my gym!
去你的拳馆
Fuck this gym!
- 这是学习阶段…-不行
-Called a learning curve… - Ain't no way.
你知道吗
Hey, hey, hey! You know what?
当你在说话你学不了任何东西 这是事实
You can't learn anything when you're talking. That's a fact of life.
只要你在说话你就没有在听
As long as you're talking, you're not listening.
去道歉 你们是同一阵线的 好吗
Go apologize. You guys are on the same damn team, okay?
- 这就对了 很好 - 你很好 没关系
-There you go. Good. - You good. It's okay.
好了 继续吧
All right. Now let's go to work!
双刺拳
Double jab. Yup.
上面
Go ahead over the top.
右勾拳这里 在这里
Right hook here. Over here.
一次一步 一次出一拳…
One step at a time, one punch at a time…
这样重复
one round at a time.
一次一步 一次出一拳…
One step at a time, one punch at a time…
这样重复 右转
one round at a time. Turn right.
来吧 继续
Come on, let's go.
快点 出拳快点
Fast, pop it fast.
很好
Good.
我要你全力以赴
I want you to let it all out.
这里
Now right here.
曾经有人人尊重你 看着他们
Everyone's ever disrespected you, see them.
一切你曾经想要的…
Anything you ever wanted…
追寻它
go after it.
你是时候发威了 摆出架势
Now's your time! Make a statement!
一步
One step!
一拳
One punch!
一步一步来
One round at a time!
好了
There it is.
你出猫
You cheated!
- 洛奇 - 你好吗 彼得
-Rock. - Hey, how you doing, Pete?
有问题吗
Something wrong?
洛奇 我知道 我知道这孩子有点猫腻
Rock, I knew. I knew there was something with this kid.
洛奇 我一直叫你回来跟我们一起做教练很多年
Rocky, I have been trying for years to get you to come work with us.
没关系
It's okay.
突然间这从好莱坞来的孩子
All of a sudden, this kid from Hollywood.
把你从阴影中拉了出来
gets you out of the shadows.
不 没有阴影
No. No shadows.
我只是不想再拳馆做事 仅此而已
I just didn't want to do nothing in the gym, that's all.
洛奇 我打了电话去洛杉矶
Rocky, I made calls to L.A.
这孩子叫阿多尼斯 是奎迪的后代
Kid's name is Adonis. Kid has Creed's blood.
现在这场拳击会变得史前轰动
Now this fight just got big time.
我很抱歉
I apologize.
帮我个忙 我们可以保守这个秘密吗
Do me a favor.Can we keep this between ourselves?
- 不是吧 - 不
-Come on. - No.
我是在请求你帮忙
I'm asking you as a favor.
我想他闯出自己的名堂
I want him to make a name on his own.
来嘛 彼得
Come on, Pete.
我会保守秘密的 洛奇
Yeah. Secret's safe with me, Rock.
我很感谢
I appreciate it.
保持状态 你状态很好
Keep going. You're looking good.
动起来
Go on, get moving.
大家今晚感觉怎么样
Hey. So how's everybody feeling tonight?
我要说下美国广播公司的规则和州管理规则
I'm about to go over the ABC rules and the rules governed by the state.
没有三次击倒规则 没有站立数八下规则
No three knockdown rule. No standing eight-count.
拳手不能被铃声所救
A fighter cannot be saved by the bell.
我们说的「没有三次击倒规则」 是什么意思呢…
What we mean by "no three knockdown rule"…
基本上就是裁判认为任何适合比赛
is basically whatever the referee sees fit for competition.
大叔 脱掉我的手套
Unc, cut my gloves off.
- 怎么了 - 我的手套 快把它脱了
-What's wrong? - My gloves, just cut 'em off!
我不能脱 你准备上场了
I can't cut 'em off, you're ready to go fight.
它们太紧了吗
Are they too tight?
我现在紧张死了 我要去拉屎
I'm freaking out right now! I gotta take a shit!
有人跟我擦屁股吗
Somebody gonna wipe my ass for me?
- 妈的 - 脱掉我的手套 大叔
-Oh, shit! - Cut my gloves off, Unc!
好了 轻松点
All right, relax.
我现在把你的手套脱了
I'll cut you out of these gloves. It happens.
裁判 我这有点麻烦
Hey, ref, I'm gonna need some help here.
- 唐 我到外面去 - 是的
-D, I'm gonna be right outside. - That's right.
你可以拖延十分钟吗
Can you just stall for 10 minutes or something?
我要把拳头戴回去
I gotta put the gloves back on.
好吧 我在外面等 洛奇
All right, I'll step on outside, Rock.
我很感谢你 非常谢谢
I appreciate it. Thank you very much.
没问题 你有十分钟时间
It ain't no problem. You got 10 minutes.
这是我的首次
First for me.
好了 没问题的
All right, come on. It'll be all right.
有点紧张吗
A little nervous?
紧张
Nerves?
快点啊
Hurry up!
蓝方 红方
Blue corner, red corner.
好了 你们都在更衣室听了规则了
All right, fellows, y'all had your intructions in the dressing room.
时刻听我的指挥 时刻保护你自己
Obey my commands at all times, protect yourself at all times.
蓝方有疑问吗 红方有疑问吗
Any questions from the blue corner? Questions from the red corner?
对拳 准备开始
Touch them up. Be ready on seconds out.
- 看你了 - 好的
-Right It's about you. - Yep Yep.
都看你了 现在这是你想要的
It's all about you. Now, you wanted this.
- 开始吧 教练 - 我希望你能赢
-Let's go, Coach. - I want you to make it happen.
- 你能做得到吗 - 开始吧
-Can you do it? - Let's do it.
- 好了 加油 - 我们赢这场比赛吧
-All right. Come on. - Let's make it happen.
开始吧 大叔
Let's go, Unc.
都看今天了
It's all about today!
不然就没明天了 加油
There is no tomorrow! Let's go!
漂亮
Nice!
移动 看准目标
Move and target, move and target!
刺拳 出刺拳
Jab! Get the jab!
他的脸空防 快啊 刺拳呢
His face is right there! Come on! Where's the jab?
举起双手 孩子
Hands up. Hands up, kid.
别着急 孩子
Breathe, kid, breathe!
来呀 来呀
Let's go, boy! Let's go, boy!
动起来 唐尼
Keep moving, Donnie!
挥拳 就这样
Move your head! That's it.
追击他
Get on him! Get on him!
分开
Break! My break!
开始
Let's go, boy!
就这样 很好
There you go! There you go! Good.
后退
Back off.
利奥
Leo! Leo! Leo!
打他的头
One punch on top.
保持移动 就这样 格挡
Keep moving. That's right. Block left. Block left.
来呀 来打我啊
Let's go, boy! Come get this shit! Come get it!
你做的很好 孩子 继续压他
You're doing good, kid! Keep the pressure up!
分开
Break!
加油啊 利奥
Let's go, Leo!
继续打 继续向前压
Keep moving! Keep coming forward!
漂亮
Great shot!
加油啊 唐尼
Come on, Donnie!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
时间到
Time!
好了
Okay! All right.
没关系的 深呼吸 大口深呼吸
It's okay. Take a deep breath. Through your lungs. Deep breath.
看着我 我喜欢在外面的架势 好吧
Look at me, I like what you doing out there, all right?
你有点紧绷 你要放松点 好吗
You're a little tight. You're gonna loosen up, all right?
这是我对你的建议 我要你往右边躲
Here's what I want you to do. I want you to throw your left under the radar.
就这样 然后上去来一拳铲勾拳
That's it. Then come up with a shovel hook.
你会看到个空挡 打到他的下巴这会让他倒下…
You're gonna see an opening, put it right on his chin, that'll drop him…
戴牙套 准备开始
Mouthpiece in, seconds out!
你老爸就这样打我 很有效
Your old man did that to me. It worked.
戴牙套 准备开始
Mouthpiece in, seconds out!
利奥
Leo! Leo! Leo!
来呀
Come on!
捆住他 就这样 好样的
Tie him up! That's it. Good boy! Tie him up!
分开
Break!
来呀
Come on!
孩子 就是现在 现在
Kid, seize it now! Now! Now!
- 起来 - 加油啊 孩子
-Get up! Get up! - Come on, kid! Come on!
- 一 二 - 起来继续
-One! Two! - Get up and get some!
三 四
Three! Four.
我们击倒他了 洛奇
We got him, Rock!
五 六
Five! Six!
七 八
Seven! Eight!
- 我没事 - 九 十
-I'm good. - Nine! Ten!
比赛结束
That's it, baby!
我们赢了一场了 洛奇
We got one, Rock!
- 我们赢了一场了 我们赢了 - 难以置信
-We got one! Yeah, we got! - Unbelievable!
- 都是因为你 - 不 是你做到的
-It's because of you! - No, you did it.
来吧 你做到了
Come on, man! You did it.
- 你没事吧 - 给他写空间 洛奇
-You okay? - Give him some room. Rock. Rock. Rock.
上来吧 比安卡 上来
Come on in! Bianca! Bianca! Come in!
抱歉
Sorry! Sorry!
你没说过你手那么有力啊
You didn't say you had hands like that!
为什么你没说过你的手那么有力
Why didn't you say you had hands like that, though?
但我很结实 我很结实
Well, but girl, I'm square though. I'm square though.
- 你没事吧 - 我们之后有什么打算
-You good? - What we doing after this?
我们继续吧
Let's go for it.
- 我们横扫全城 - 好的
-Let's got tear the city up! - Okay.
我给你做了点东西
I make something for you!
你感觉怎么样
So, how are you feel?
我很好
I'm okay!
有一点脚软 但没事
A little soft, but all right.
你要吐司吗
You want some toast?
好的
OKay.
你在看什么
What are you watching?
我在看你
I'm looking you up.
- 你说做什么 - 我在看你
-You're doing what? - I'm looking you up.
不 别这样 我还在呢
No, don't do that. I'm right here.
怎么了
What's up?
你有些什么想告诉我的吗
You got something you wanna tell me?
我没有说谎
I didn't lie.
你也许没有 你告诉我你爸爸是个拳手
You might as well have. You told me that your dad was some fighter.
你没说他是个最出名的拳手
You didn't say he was the most famous fighter ever lived.
当他们知道后大家看我就不同了
People look at me differently when they know.
他们看阿波罗也是不同
They look at Apollo differently too.
是啊 唐尼 但我不是那些人
Yeah, Donnie. But I'm not people.
我不在乎那些事
I don't care about that shit.
但我很在乎你隐瞒我
I do care about you keeping it 100% with me, though.
听着 你是对的 好吗
Well, listen. You're right, okay?
不 说真的 你…
No, seriously, look. You…
现在开始不隐瞒任何事
100% honesty from here on out.
好吧 那他的…他的妻子是你的妈妈吗
All right. So his… His wife, tht's not your mom?
阿波罗跟我妈妈有婚外情
Apollo had an affair with my mom.
好了吗 她在我小时候就死了
All right? She died when I was young.
几年来我一直被寄养
I bounced around foster care for a couple years.
在少管所经常出入
In and out of juvie.
然后玛丽 安妮找到我 把我收养了
Then Mary Anne tracked me down and took me in.
还有问题吗
Anything else?
问我吧
Ask me.
在我之前你跟过几个女孩子一起
How many females have you been with before me?
还有其他吗
Anything else?
听着 比安卡 你不同
Look, Bianca, come on now, you different.
怎么说
How?
当我在你身边我感觉就像知道你是我的生命
When I'm around you I feel like I know you my whole life.
告诉我你跟我没有同样的感觉
Tell me you don't feel the same way about me.
随便吧 这是激情 这是热恋 这会过去的
Whatever. That's in passion. That's infatuation. That fades.
- 我可看不出来 - 为什么看不出
-I can't see that happening. - Why not?
- 你激励我 - 好吧 所以我只是你的动机
-You motivate me. - Okay, so I'm just motivation to you?
你是不是要把我的话全都找茬
Are you gonna find a problem with everything I say?
不 我要找出你说的话真实的部分
No, I'm gonna find the real in what you're saying.
别担心 没关系 也许你也是只是我的动机
Don't worry, it's cool. Maybe you're just motivation to me, too.
是吗
Oh, really?
我不介意
I don't mind that.
干嘛
What?
- 但你真的很像他 - 我的天 我讨厌死了
-You do look like him, though. - Oh, my God. I hate that!
把我搞得紧张死了
Just to get on my nerves!
欢迎收看PTI 我们今天的首条新闻是拳击新闻
Welcome to PTI, boys and girls. We begin today with the boxing world.
阿多尼斯 约翰逊…
Adonis Johnson…
一个小小的拳手被洛奇 巴尔博亚训练…
a little-known boxer being trained by Rocky Balboa…
轻量级冠军争夺者…
handed light heavyweight title contender…
利奥 斯皮诺昨晚在费城第二回合被技术击倒
Leo Sporino a second-round TKO defeat in Philadelphia last night.
一位匿名人士向ESPN证实约翰逊…
An anonymous source confirmed to ESPN that Johnson…
是阿波罗 奎迪最小的亲生儿子
is the youngest biological son of Apollo Creed.
这事实一直保持秘密是因为…
Fact that was kept under wraps because…
约翰逊是奎迪的私生子
Johnson was the product of Creed's infidelity.
拳击界很兴奋有另一个奎迪在擂台上…
The boxing world is excited to have another Creed in the ring…
但威尔伯 这件事会破坏阿波罗 奎迪的传奇吗
but, Wilbon, does knowledge of this affair damage Apollo Creed's legacy?
破坏他的传奇
Damage his legacy?
让我们说回以前 阿波罗 奎迪的小历史回顾
Let's go back for a second. A little history on Apollo Creed.
我很确定他在生的时候也许是最强的
I certainly have him right up there, as maybe the best of all time.
讨论结束
End of discussion.
他失算了 他犯错了就像很多人一样
He slipped. He made a mistake, like a lot of people.
这不会是拳击界首次特别大的事
This isn't gonna be the first, particularly in the boxing world!
是的
Yeah.
但我不会说这会抹杀了他的传奇
But I'm not gonna say it's gonna kill his legacy!
我觉得这是件难堪的事…
I think it's an embarrassment…
而且我认为他的家庭一定感到很尴尬…
and I think the family must have felt this embarrassment…
因为他们保守秘密这么长时间
because they kept it under wraps for so long.
- 但我有一个问题 - 什么
-But I really have one question. - What?
这孩子有他老爸那么厉害吗
Can the kid fight as well as the old man?
这太扯了
That's a stretch.
我找到我们下一个招财猫
I found us our next payday.
看看吧
Check it out.
- 奎迪之子 - 没错
-Creed's son? - Yeah.
- 你跟我开玩笑吗 - 不
-Are you kidding me? - No.
他只打了一场比赛
He's got one fight under his belt.
没错 我知道 但他有巴尔博亚做教练
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, I know. But he's got Balboa in his corner.
没有人会在乎巴尔博亚了
No one cares about Balboa anymore.
选这小孩就因为一个名字
Kid's here because of a name alone.
你要去打
You're gonna do it.
这家伙不值得比赛
This guy doesn't even deserve a shot.
给我听好 这不是在商讨 好吧
Listen to me. This is not a negotiation, all right?
你只是个拿着枪在
You're the idiot that ran around.
托克斯泰斯到处跑的白痴 你还记得吗
Toxteth with a gun. Do you remember that?
而且你是一个无法控制自己赛前体重的小丑…
And you are the clown who couldn't control himself at a weigh-in…
还在赌博中输了我们数百万 是几百万 所以再看一次
and lost us millions in the process. Millions, okay? So look at it again.
- 我不想这样名留青史 - 我不在乎你怎么被记住
-I don't wanna be remembered like this. - I don't care how you're remembered.
我在乎的是当你赢了后你的小孩有瓦遮顶
I care about your kids having a roof over their head when you're done.
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
你好
Hello?
我是汤米 霍利戴 我瑞奇 康兰的代理人
It's Tommy Holiday. I look after Ricky Conlan.
- 你好吗 - 听着
-Yeah, how you doing? - Listen.
那孩子的事是真的吗
Is it true about the kid?
那孩子的事
About the kid?
你和那孩子有三十分钟时间谈谈吗
Think you and the kid have got 30 minutes for a business meeting?
好吧 如果你能过来这里当然可以
All right, I'll tell you what. Yeah, if you can get over here, sure.
我们会跟你谈谈 但必须要快因为我们在训练
We'll talk with you, but it's gotta be fast because we're training.
- 我几天后可以过去 - 好吧
-I can be there. Couple of days. - Yeah.
保持联络
I'll be in touch.
好的
Okay.
天啊
Oh, man.
谢谢你们的时间 我就直接说了
Thanks for taking the time. I'll be right to it.
我的人需要在接下来的六个月里打一场…
My guy needs to fight in the next six months…
而我们已经击败了所有人
and we've beaten everybody.
你想我跟康兰打
You want me to fight Conlan?
我觉得这是一个很明智的选择
I think it would be a very wise move.
你在墨西哥做过职业拳手
You've been down in Mexico doing pro fights?
我看到你在那15赢0败
I've got you as 15-0 down there.
而加上斯皮诺那一场 你就是16赢0败了
And with the Sporino fight, that makes you 16-0.
现在没有人想知道那些无名拳手的 是吧
Now, nobody needs to know these fights on some hole in the wall, do they?
你觉得我可以吗
You think I'm ready?
唐尼 这男人来是因为他知道你很安全
Donnie, this man came here because he knows you're a sure thing.
- 是吧 这是稳稳的胜利 - 不是这样的
-Right? It's a sure victory. - That is not true.
就是这样
Yeah, it is.
好了 听着
Okay, listen.
好吧
All right.
这可能是我的人最后一场比赛了
This could be my guy's last fight.
我想把它搞得有所期待 在那报纸上…
And I wanna make it count. Now, on that note…
我们需要你把姓改成奎迪 这只是一种形式
We would need you to change your name to Creed. It's just a formality.
那如果我说不呢
And what if I say no?
那…就没有比赛 不改名就没有比赛
Well, then… there's no fight. Without the name, there's no fight.
太默默无名了
It's a non-starter.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
要不你们用一天时间考虑…
Why don't you both take a day, talk about it…
我们再看你怎么样吧 好吗
and we'll see what you say, okay?
这是笔好交易
It's a good deal.
做不到 这不是我的名字
Can't do it. Nah, it's not my name.
而且我想这是出于我的自身价值
And plus, I wanna make it on my own merit anyway.
- 是吗 - 是的
-Yeah? - Yeah.
你可以用搞笑的方式来表现出来
You got a funny way of showing it.
那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
阿波罗和洛奇不是像最好的朋友吗
I mean, weren't Apollo and Rocky like best friends?
这感觉就像你在挖掘他留下的什么
It feels like you're trying to tap into whatever it is he left behind.
我不认为这又什么可耻的 你明白吗
I don't think that's anything to be ashamed of, you know?
- 你害怕什么 - 你害怕什么
-What are you afraid of? - What are you afraid of?
我不知道
I don't know.
我意思是这听力的问题没有让你害怕吗
I mean this hearing shit don't scare you?
我一直知道最终的结果…
I always knew it would happen eventually…
所以我总是计划…
so my plan has always just been…
尽可能的做我喜欢做的事
to do what I love for as long as I can.
我认为这是我们的本能
I think that's all we ever do. You know?
那么你害怕什么
So, what are you afraid of?
我害怕拿起这名字又失去了
I'm afraid of taking on the name and losing.
他们会叫我骗子 假奎迪
They'll call me a fraud. Fake Creed.
为什么你不想想事实是什么
Why don't you think about what's true?
你很喜欢拳击 对吧
You love to fight, right?
- 它让你很开心 对吧 - 没错
-Yeah, it makes you happy, right? - Yeah.
而且你是阿波罗 奎迪的儿子 对吧
Yeah, and you are Apollo Creed's son, right?
- 是的 - 那就用这名字啊
-Yes. - So then use the name.
这是你的名字
It's yours.
- 大叔 你在下面吗 - 是的
-Hey, Unc, you down there? - Yeah.
我知道你不想我去打这场比赛 对吧
I know you don't want me to do this, right?
我可以想到什么是最好的 唐尼
I can think of better things to do, Donnie.
但如果我们要去打…
But if we did do it…
我们要怎么才能赢
how we get it done?
他比你高 他手比你长
He's taller than you. He has a reach on you.
经验肯定比你丰富
Definitely has a lot more experience than you.
他比你速度快 他是冠军
And he's faster than you are. He's the champion.
而且自从他是冠军后…
And since he's the champion…
你得向他挑战 就像我以前一样
you gotta bring the fight to him, like I did.
你得打近身 而你这样做…
You gotta go to the body. Dig. And in doing that…
你会非常危险 因为你有可能被击倒
you're in a very dangerous place because you can get laid out.
要我在你这处境也不容易啊 小孩
It ain't easy for me to be in your corner, kid.
我不知道你准备好没有 我不知道我准备好没有
I don't know if you're ready for it. I don't know if I'm ready for it.
但我会按你想的做
But I'll do what you wanna do.
如果是其他人做我教练…
If it was anybody else in my corner…
我就不会打了
I wouldn't do it.
但我有你
But I got you.
所以下决定吧
So make the call.
好吧
All right.
我要跟瑞奇 康兰打了
I'm fighting Ricky Conlan.
我要跟「漂亮」 瑞奇 康兰打了
I'm fighting "Pretty" Ricky Conlan!
- 别累坏他了 洛奇 - 好的
-Don't work him too hard, Rock. - Yeah.
他还是只小狗
He's still a puppy.
来吧
Come on, come on.
近距离 就这样
Close the distance. That's it.
很好
Good.
来吧 打身体 这里
Come on. Body, come here.
这一击不错
Yeah. Got a good hit.
好了
Okay.
来吧
Come on.
用力 打身体 很好
Dig deep. Body, body, body. Good.
你可以继续吗
You up to moving around?
休息下
Take a break.
大叔 你没事吧
Hey, Unc, you all right?
- 我没事 - 你还好吗
-I'm all right. - You okay?
我没事 吐出来了
I'm all right. It's out.
- 我没事 - 好吧
-I'm all right. - All right.
让我缓缓
Just let me walk.
我没事
Just… I'm good.
- 确定 - 没事
-Sure? - Yeah.
你是怎么了
Hey. What's wrong with you?
我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
我扶你
Come here.
让我走走
Just let me walk.
不 我们要叫人给你找医生 好吗
No, we got to call someone and get you to the doctor, okay?
- 好的 - 好了 来吧
-Okay. - All right, come on.
- 下擂台 我帮你 - 别紧张
-Off the rope. Come on, I got you. - Easy.
史迪奇
Hey, Stitch!
- 我很抱歉 - 不 不 什么
-I'm sorry. - No, no. What?
不 我真的…
No, I'm really…
来人帮忙啊
Hey, somebody help!
你好
Hi.
- 你好 - 唐尼
-Hi. - Donnie.
凯瑟里医生
Dr. Kathari.
巴尔博亚先生 你感觉怎么样
Mr. Balboa, how you feeling?
我感觉很好 真的很好 我现在可以走了
I'm feeling good, real good. I could go now.
听说你倒下了 这是你第一次倒下吗
Heard you fell down. Was that the first time you've fallen?
第一次不是被击倒的
Well, without being punched.
我会给你些液体 这应该会让你感觉好点
I'm gonna give you some more fluids. That should help you feel better.
我们早上回给你做些检测然后让你离开
And we're gonna run some tests in the morning and get you out of here.
你可以做快点吗 因为我们有很多事情做
Can you do this fast? Because we got a lot of stuff to do.
轻松点 好吗 睡觉吧
Just relax. All right? Go to sleep.
我稍后再来看你
I'll check on you later.
谢谢
Thank you.
必须要快 我们必须…
Gotta do it fast. We have to…
- 唐尼 我们还要训练 - 睡觉吧
-Donnie, we gotta train. - Yeah, go to sleep.
你们需要帮忙吗
You guys need any more help?
- 不 我们很好 - 不 我们很好 谢谢
-No! We're good. - No, we're good, thank you!
- 你行吗 你需要什么 - 我以为你早拿出来了
-You got it? What you need? - Thought you got lost for a minute.
没有
Nothing, nothing.
我在这房子从来没见过像这样的食物
I have not seen food look like this in this house ever.
是吗
Yeah?
是的 通常我有的都是酱汁或酱菜什么的
Yes. You know, usually everything I have has sauce or something on it.
来点这些羽衣甘蓝
Get some of these collard greens.
好吧 你就…
All right. Yo just…
- 就来一点 - 来一点
-Just a little bit? - Yeah, a little bit.
比安卡 你很漂亮…
Bianca, you're beautiful…
而且我认为你会成为一个很棒的歌手
and I think you'll be a great singer.
我觉得你会成为一个很棒的冠军 像你父亲一样
I think you're gonna be a great champ, like your father.
也许甚至更好
Maybe even better.
而我很幸运可以认识你们俩
And for me, who's lucky enough to be knowing both of you guys.
来干杯 百年好合 一百年
Here we go. Cent'anni. 100 years.
- 我很荣幸 - 我真幸运
-I'm honored. - Lucky me.
继续练铲勾拳
Keep working on that shovel hook.
对 就这样
Right, that's it.
在同一边挥出勾拳
Now, wanna throw the hook on the same side.
那么你从左边上你就出右拳
So you come up on the right, you throw on the right.
非常好
Very good.
要凶猛一点 有力一些
A little more vicious than that, little more power.
重复做 非常好
Overdo it. Yeah! Very good.
洛奇
Hey, Rock.
是
Yeah.
很好 你干得不错
Good. You're looking good.
- 你在吃醋吗 - 有一点
-Are you getting jealous? - Yeah, a little.
- 你的电话 - 谢谢
-It's for you. - Thanks.
你好 是吗 是的
Hello? Yeah? Yeah.
是的 好的
Yeah, okay.
好的 谢谢
All right, thanks.
巴尔博亚先生
Mr. Balboa.
谢谢你赶时间过来
Thanks for coming in on such short notice.
我们看了你的检测结果…
Well, we went through your test results…
你的活检显示大细胞非霍奇金淋巴瘤
and your biopsy came back showing signs of large cell non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.
这是什么
What's that do?
这是一种癌症
Well, it's a form of cancer.
我知道这听起来很恐怖 但好消息是我们及早发现它了
I know that sounds scary, but the good news is we caught it early.
然而我们必须切除在你淋巴结…
However, we will have to remove the tumor…
的肿瘤和立即开始化疗
in your lymph nodes and start chemotherapy immediately.
我妻子试过了
My wife tried that.
巴尔博亚现在 目前的治疗选择…
Mr. Balboa, as far as options for treatment…
这是最好的方法了
this is the best plan of action.
不 我明白 但我的妻子试过了…
No, I understand, but my wife tried that…
而我认为我不想这样做
and I don't think I wanna do it.
结果不怎么好 但没关系
Didn't turn out so good. But it's okay.
有治疗 你还是有很大机会痊愈的
With treatment, you'll still have a very good chance of recovery.
没有治疗的话…
Without it…
- 我没关系 真的 - 起码把这些拿去
-I'm okay with it, really. - Well, at least take these.
这有你的诊断和治疗方案的信息
It has information on your diagnosis and options for treatment.
- 我们可以先从…-非常感谢
-We can start… - Thank you very much.
听着 如果你不跟别人说我会很感激你的 好吧
Listen, I'd appreciate if you wouldn't say nothing to nobody, okay?
塞车塞死了 说你也不相信
Oh, man! There's so much traffic, you wouldn't believe it.
老年人专用公交晚点了 对吧
That senior bus was running late, huh?
这笑话很低俗
Hey, that's a cheap shot.
- 这是事实 - 上擂台
-It's the truth. - Get in the ring.
- 快点准备好 - 我已经准备好了
-Hurry up and get ready. - I've been ready.
很好
Good.
我一直在等你
I've been waiting on you.
来吧 带上你的拳套别说那么多废话
Come on, just put your gloves on and stop talking so much.
我们有几件事要做 都是关于你的
We got a few things to do. It's all about you.
我已经有我的事业了 我做得很好
I already had my career. I did okay.
你的借口是什么 你没有借口
What's your excuse? You got no excuse.
现在是时候你升到那个场合了
Now is the time for you to rise to the occasion there.
- 只是要戴上我的…-我来帮你
-Just gonna put my… - I can do it.
好了
Okay, all right.
现在…
Now…
我要你一直首先重视你自己
I want you to always, always, always pay attention to yourself first.
如果我不在这里就自己先练
If I'm not here to start with, just start moving around.
好吧 牙套 知道我什么意思吗
All right. Mouthpiece. Know what I'm saying?
头被打太多拳了 对吧
Too many punches to the head, huh?
随便吧 教练
Yeah, whatever, coach.
好了 上场吧 冠军
All right, get going there, champ.
贝尔
Bell.
来吧 奎迪
Come on, Creed!
做第一 唐尼 快
Be first, Donnie. Come on!
回见 阿米尔
All right, Amir.
回见 冠军 别累坏了
All right, champ. Don't work too hard.
这是真的吗
This shit for real?
无所谓了
Doesn't matter.
你应该想的是比赛日快要到了
What you should be thinking about is that fight coming up.
这是你唯一应该放在心上的事 没其他了
That's the only thing that should be on your mind, nothing else.
你说不要想这个是什么意思 你什么时候开始治疗
What you mean, don't think about this? When you starting treatment?
我不做化疗 不
I'm not doing no chemotherapy. No.
如果你不快点做你很快就会死的
If you don't jump on this quick, you're gonna end up dying.
我知道
I know.
而你没关系
And you're all right with that?
是的
I am.
天啊 你听起来是疯了
Man, you sound crazy, man.
把钥匙给我 我马上带你去医院
Give me the keys. I'll take you to the hospital right now.
我没有疯
I'm not crazy at all.
如果我以前可以把一切东西…
If I could take everything that was good…
放到碗里或什么的…
and put it into a bowl or something…
然后说「这里 我想给我妻子多买一天时间」…
and say, "Hey! Here. I'd like to buy one more day with my wife"…
我也愿意
I'd do it.
那我死也是个开心的男人
I would die a happy man, right then.
不可能的
Not gonna happen.
所以…
So…
我能做的只是向前进而我还在
everything I got has moved on and I'm here.
但你知道什么吗 这没关系
But you know what? It's okay.
因为我对自己说「如果我要死了
Because I said to myself, "If I break,
如果我受伤了 不管了
if I'm hurt, whatever.
我不会去解决 为什么要自寻烦恼「
"I ain't gonna fix it. Why bother?"
而我只是住在你的小床的流浪汉 什么也不是
And I'm just some bum just living in your crib, just nothing.
你是个好孩子 好拳手
You're a good kid, a good fighter.
你前面还有大把前途
But you got your whole future ahead of you.
我呢
Mine?
在后面 像他们那样在墙上
Back there, like all them guys on that wall.
在后面 在过去
In the back, in the past.
我们没有未来了
We re going nowhere.
我对你来说只是个老教练
I am to you just an old trainer.
这是我们一起的原因 你明白吗
That's what brought us together. You know?
我们不是真的家人
We're not a real family.
那只是说气话而已 孩子
That was just in our heads, kid.
你做了什么
What'd you do? What'd you do?
你为什么这么说
Why did you say that?
怎么了 小奎迪
Hey, what's up, Lil Creed?
很好
It's good.
- 嘿 - 怎么了 兄弟
-Oh, hey! - What's up, bro?
- 嘿 - 你好吗
-Hey! - What up?
你还好吗
You okay?
你怎么样 你好吗
Yeah. How you doing? You good?
我很好 我有点紧张
Yeah, I'm good I'm a little nervous.
只是有很多人在这 不都是我的粉丝
There's just a lot of people here. not really my crowd, you know?
我明白
Yeah, I can see.
看 这是打拳男孩 小阿波罗 奎迪
Look, it's the boxing boy. Lil Apollo Creed.
我认识他的女朋友
I know his girl.
- 你好吗 比安卡 - 嘿
-What's up, Bianca? - Hey.
你不认识我了吗
You don't know nobody no more?
不 我经过的时候跟你打招呼了
Nah, I said hello to you when I walked past.
你没回应我
You didn't say nothing to me.
我猜你有的 别再学白人那一套了
Yeah, I bet you did. Stop acting light-skinned.
要不你过来这里…
Hey, man, why don't you come over here…
跟我一起和拍个照
and grab this pic with me real quick for the 'Gram?
没问题
Yeah, that's cool.
快点 你知道他忙
Come on, man. You know he busy, man.
欢迎来到我的城市 冠军
Welcome to my city, champ.
- 好了 阿比 - 好的
-There it is, Abbie. - Believe dat.
看好你 婴儿奎迪
Hey, good looking, Baby Creed.
别这么叫我
Don't call me that.
别这么叫你 别叫你什么
Don't call you that? Don't call you what?
你刚叫我「婴儿奎迪」 我说了别这么叫我
You just called me "Baby Creed". I said, don't call me that.
我是对你客气
Hey, fam, dig this. I was showing you love, man.
你没必要这么啊
You ain't got to come off like that.
没关系 客气而已
Yo, that's cool, that's all love.
- 我知道没关系 - 你肯定没关系啊
-I know it's cool. - You definitely know it's cool.
当你跟我说话 你好像很屌的样子啊
When you talking to me, you talking real tough, you feel me?
最好跟你的小帅哥男朋友说说
Better talk to your little pretty boy boyfriend, man.
拿个贵宾通行卡到你的房间 这样跟我说话
Get a VIP pass next to your pop, talking to me like that.
不
No!
别激动 黑鬼
Hold up, nigga!
唐尼
Donnie! Donnie! Donnie!
唐尼 别打了
Donnie! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
我会宰了你
I'll kill your ass!
唐尼
Donnie! Donnie!
- 他怎么样了 - 他现在没事了
-How's he doing? - He's all right now.
- 你知道怎么回事吗 - 我们要把他隔离
-You know what happened? - We had to separate him.
他跟另一些囚犯打架
He was fighting with the other inmates.
不 有人受伤了吗
Oh, no. Anybody get hurt?
没有 没有生命危险
Nah, nothing life-threatening.
- 好的 谢谢 - 没问题 冠军
-All right, thank you. - No problem, champ.
好的
Yeah.
唐尼
Hey, Donnie.
你怎么样了 儿子
How you doing, son?
我知道有很多警察说「你的朋友被锁了」
I know a lot of cops and they said, "Your friend's locked up."
朋友 你对我来说只是教练 对吧
Friends? You're just a trainer to me, right?
我很抱歉之前在拳馆我对你说的话
I'm sorry about what I said to you, back at the gym.
那只是我自言自语 我不是那个意思
That was just me talking. I didn't mean it.
你离我远点
You just stay away from me.
听着 唐尼…
Listen, Donnie…
- 别碰我 - 别这样…
-Man, don't touch me. - Come on, what…
放开你的手 老家伙
Get your hands off me, old man!
你快滚出去
Get your sick ass out of here!
离开
Leave!
你来这里装到好像我家人似的
You here talking like you my family!
你害死了我真正的家人
You got my real family killed!
我不会离开…直到我把心里的话告诉你
I ain't leaving… till I tell you what's on my mind.
你讨厌我 就是这样
You hate me, that's what it is.
或者也许你对某个不在这的人 唐尼…
Or maybe you're mad with somebody who ain't here, Donnie…
一个不能为自己辩护的人
who can't defend himself.
你知道吗
You know?
我明白你在经历什么 年轻人 我也经历过
Now, I understand what you're going through, young man. I've been there.
我知道被遗弃是什么感觉…
And I know what it's like to feel abandoned…
对一切都很愤怒
to be mad at everything.
而你是比那更好的人
And you're a better person than that.
原谅他吧 因为对他什么也做不了
Forgive him. Because there's nothing you can do about it.
这影响了你
It's taking a toll on you.
你还在追寻他的背影
You're still caught in his shadow.
- 你得向前看 唐尼 - 快离开
-You got to move, Donnie. - Just leave, man.
走吧 约翰逊
Let's go, Johnson.
比安卡
Bianca!
你别再像警察那样敲我的门了
Yol Stop knocking on my door like the police.
- 你能起码让我道歉吗 - 不 没有用的
-Can you at least let me apologize? - No, it doesn't work like that.
当你把饮料洒到别人身上道歉 可以
You apologize when you spill a drink on someone, sure.
但你袭击去我表演的嘉宾…
But you assaulted the headliner to my show…
一个我很努力争取回来的演出机会
a show I worked really hard to get.
如果我去你比赛耍流氓呢
What if I came to your fight acting like an ass?
你会没意见吗
Would that be cool with you?
不 我不认为
Nah, I didn't think so.
后来你怎么样 你取消了吗
How'd you do though? You kill it?
我们演出得很好
Yeah, we did good.
我搞砸了我是活该的 好吧
I messed that up and I gotta live with that, all right?
但我从没想让你失望
But I never meant to let you down.
那你是什么意思 自负吗
Then what did you mean to do, D? Just have a little ego contest?
洛奇病了
Rocky's sick.
他有癌症
He's got cancer.
我不是想为我所做的找借口…
I ain't trying to make excuses for anything that I did…
但我刚在你演出前发现了
but I found out right before your show.
有多严重
How bad is it?
他们想让他开始化疗 但你知道他太臭脾气不去做
They want him to start chemo but, you know, he's too macho to do that.
天啊
Jesus.
也许你可以劝他去
Well, maybe you can talk some sense into him.
我不认为他想听我说
I don't think he'd wanna hear anything I got to say.
替我向他问好
Yeah, well, give him my love.
比安卡 现在别拒我门外
Hey, Bianca, don't close me out right now.
听着 我们现在都有很多事在进行…
Look, we both got a lot going on right now…
所以我想你应该专注在你的事业而我专注我的
so I think you should focus on yours and I'm gonna focus on mine.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
这什么意思
What's that mean?
我明白我搞砸了
I get it, I messed up.
我相信你 能请你别拒我门外吗
I trusted you! Can you please not shut me out?
我很抱歉 好吗
I'm sorry, okay?
我现在需要你
I need you right now.
黑鬼 怎么了
Nigga, what's up?
你好吗
What's up?
我听说你是阿波罗 奎迪的儿子
Hey, I heard you Apollo Creed's son.
没错
Yeah.
那很屌
That's what up.
你看起来瘦了五磅 你应该坐下来吃饭了
Look like you lost five pounds. You ought to sit down and eat.
我像什么
I mean, what I look like?
让你训练我的同时你在等死
Letting you train me while you sit around and die?
就像其他比赛一样
Just like any other fight.
这场比赛 我以前见过
This fight? I seen it before.
这会越来越糟糕…
It gets as bad as it can get…
而且大多时候你赢不了
and most of the time, you don't win it.
但我不在乎
Yeah, but I don't care.
如果你不接受治疗我就不训练
I ain't training if you don't get the treatment.
所以我战 你也战
So if I fight, you fight.
- 嘿 - 怎么样
-Hey. - What's up?
- 你去拳馆了 - 不 我一直在这
-You been to the gym? - Nah, I've been here.
好了 记得这个吗
Okay. Here you go. Remember this?
起来
Get up.
- 准备好了吗 - 这是…
-Ready? - What's…
我要你做拳击训练
I want you to shadow box.
这房间不错 我们在这训练吧
This is a nice room, let's see you move around.
你认真的吗
You're serious?
- 要我替你做吗 - 不 没问题
-Want me to do it for you? - No. It's all good.
- 准备好了吗 - 来吧
-Yeah, ready? - Come on.
计时
Time!
就这样
There you go.
我们以前是单手做的
We used to do that with one hand.
但我就不说什么了
I don't wanna say anything though.
别打那位小姐
Don't hit the lady.
她可能会打倒你的
She'll probably drop you.
好了撑住 快到了
All right.Come on, almost there.
坚持住 大叔
Come on, Unc.
天啊
Oh, God.
就这样
That's your thing, yes!
用力
More! Yes!
一片还是两片 医生说两片的
One. Two? The deal was two!
我不能 不
I can't, no.
我头晕
I'm dizzy.
双刺拳
Double jab.
打到这里
Step on right under there.
很好
Good.
起码我们有进步
At least we got the speed.
我们只需要他坐下那么当他出击 他就打破它
We just need him to sit down so when he hits something, he breaks it.
很好
Good.
贴紧它 你必须贴紧它 来呀
Step with it, you gotta step with it. Come on!
再贴紧点
Little bit more.
再贴紧点 用力 很好
Little bit more, dig down. Good.
很好 保持这样
Good. Keep it right.
- 看 他在做同样的事 - 没错 看来是这样的
-Look, he's doing the same thing. - Yeah, he does, it looks that way.
但我认为他给你准备了些什么
But I think he's got something up his sleeve for you.
漂亮
Wow, beautiful.
- 你在去看洛奇吗 - 没错 走吧
-Yo, you going to see Rock? - Yeah, let's go!
我们挺你 走吧
We got you! Let's go!
创造历史 奎迪 我们走吧
Make history, Creed! Let's go!
你们好吗 来一起跑吧
What up? Come on y'all! Let's ride! Come on!
我就喜欢这样
That's what I like, man!
我们去前街看洛奇 跟我走
Let's go see Rock on Front Street! Ride with me!
你想打招呼吗
You wanna say hello?
- 这地方看起来像教堂 - 感觉像艺术博物馆
-Place looks like a church. - Yeah, fell like an art museum.
很漂亮
Yeah, beautiful.
拳击明星在两分钟内进来
The fight starts in about two minutes.
只要他一出现他就会从你那开始
As soon as he shows up, he's gonna start on you.
好的
Okay.
别让他耍到你
Don't let him get to you.
感谢你们的到来 我们直接开始问答环节
Okay, great. Thank you all for coming. Let's get straight into questions.
左边的那位年轻小姐
Young lady to the left.
康兰 我们能期待在赛前称重又出问题吗
Conlan, can we expect any more fireworks at the weigh-in?
我一直有去做愤怒管理…
I've been doing some anger management classes…
尽量控制我的脾气
and trying to control temper of mine.
我只是会确保他会在星期六晚上被遗忘掉
I just gonna make sure he forgets it all by Saturday night.
好了 下一个问题
Okay, next question.
戴眼镜的年轻男子
Young man in the glasses.
你们之间的差异是什么
What about the contrast between you two?
你一夜成名与康兰白手起家的背景
You, the overnight success versus Conlan's rags to riches background.
那一夜没任何变化 我一直奋斗…
Nothing happened overnight. I've been fighting for some time now…
那正是这个家伙
That's exactly how it happened for this guy.
他是一个一夜成名的人 从来没有梦想要打拼
He's an overnight success, never had a damn fight in his life.
他有这次机会是因为他用上了这名字
He's got this shot because he found that name last night.
再一个问题 有很多人说这场拳赛是传奇之战
One more. There's a lot of talk about legacy in this fight.
约翰逊 你有什么感想
Johnson, can you speak to that?
我一直想做出属于我自己的传奇
Yeah, I've been working on trying to build my own legacy.
传奇
Legacy?
我们不是开玩笑吧
Are we at some kind of comedy club?
在他旁边的家伙 这才是我们说的传奇
The guy next to him, now that's what we're talking about legacy.
- 而我就是继承人 - 别管他
-And I'm cut from that cloth. - Don't fall for it.
我父亲在码头工作
My father worked on the docks.
他的父亲是世界重量级冠军
His father was heavyweight champion of the world.
- 想那里银汤匙的人…-你一点也不了解我
-People like silver spoon over there… - You don't know nothing about me.
我够了解你的
I know enough about you.
- 我在这里了 - 你是自己过来的
-I'm here now though. I'm here now. - You found yourself here.
你是假奎迪
You a false Creed.
好吧 我现在就给你看看 我老爸不在这里
All right, I'll show you right now. My pops ain't here.
坐下
Sit down!
你想在这打 我一于奉陪
You wanna fight here? I'll do it right now!
我可以现在来 婊子 我们可以现在来打
I can do it right now, bitch! We can do it right now!
奎迪个屁
"Creed" my asshole!
- 你没事吧 - 我没事
-Yo, you okay? - Yeah, I'm all right.
好吧 你走着瞧
Okay, we'll see what's up.
我会揍死你的
I'm gonna knock that smile off your face.
唐尼 是洛奇
Yo, Donnie, it's Rock.
大叔 你没事吧
Unc, you okay?
我没事 只是睡不着
Yeah, I'm good. Just couldn't sleep.
我也是
Yeah, me either.
- 我可以坐下来吗 - 当然
-Is it okay I sit down? - Course.
唐尼…
Donnie…
当比赛完后我想你帮我个忙
I'd like you to do me a favor when all this is over.
- 没问题 任何事 - 好的 很好
-Yeah, anything. - Okay, good.
这不是很重要但我只是想把它收好 好吗
It's not important but I just wanna lock it in, okay?
- 可以 - 好的
-Yeah, you got it. - There you go.
- 你没事吧 - 没事 干嘛
-You okay? - Yeah, why?
不 你一直看着门
No, you keep looking at the door.
- 你有听到什么吗 - 没有
-Do you hear something? - No.
- 那是谁 - 我不知道
-Who is that? - I don't know.
你好吗 比安卡 你在这里干嘛
How you doing, Bianca? What are you doing here?
我受够你们两个了
Y'all two are killing me.
还有听着 你们可以就…
Oh, and listen. Would you guys just keep…
我们知道了
We know.
- 脚软的问题 - 没错
-Leg thing. - Yeah.
- 脚软 好吧 - 这很重要
-The legs, yeah. - It's important.
知道了
Got you.
- 你想进来吗 - 好
-You wanna come in? - Yeah.
请进
Please.
- 我知道了 - 很好
-I got it. - Good.
很好
All right.
很多房间
A lot of room.
一个周末来说还不够多惊喜吗
Didn't we have enough surprises for one weekend?
与我无关
That's not me.
创出你自己的传奇 妈妈上
颜色很好看
Very nice colors.
你要不拿去其他房间穿上看合不合适
Why don't you take 'em into the other room and see how well they fit.
好的
Yeah.
冠军
Hey, champ.
唐尼 我为你自豪
All right, Donnie. I'm proud of you.
这会带给他运气的
That's gonna bring him luck.
你以前从没在这么多人面前 对吧
You never been in front of this many people before, right?
这不重要
That don't matter.
你从来没离家这么远
You're never been this far away from home.
这不重要
That don't matter.
重要的是你在擂台留下了什么和你带走了什么
What matters is what you leave in that ring and what you take back with you.
你知道是什么吗
You know what that is?
骄傲
Pride.
我知道你尽力了
I know that you did your best.
而你要为了你自己奋斗
And you're doing it for yourself.
不是为了我 不是为了你父亲的往事 是为了你
Not for me, not for your father's memory, but for you.
我能从你的眼里看出…
I can see in your eyes…
你会做得到的
you're gonna do it.
现在热身吧
Let's go now.
将军
Padman.
打这里
Fight's right here.
继续
Let's go.
很好
Yeah.
左勾拳组合 来
Left hook combination, go!
- 很好 - 来吧 继续
-Yeah. - Come on, man. There you go!
上面
Go up top.
好了 伙计们是时候了 我们去赢冠军回来吧
All right, guys, it's time. Let's go win a championship!
- 到时间了 - 我们走吧
-It's time, baby. - Let's go, guys.
来吧
Come on, man.
出发吧
Let's go.
我总是在这种时候紧张…
I'd always get nervous during times like this…
但这是正常的而且这会给你活力
but that's normal and it's gonna give you energy.
很正常
Very normal. Very normal.
上去让他瞧瞧你是谁
Go up there and show him who you are!
这是你追求的也是你得到的
This is what you wanted, and what you got.
我希望你享受它 好吗 享受它
And I want you to enjoy it, okay? Do that.
康兰
Conlan! Conlan!
又见面了 我是吉姆 兰普勒 瑞奇 康兰出来了
Hello again. I'm Jim Lampley. Here comes Ricky Conlan.
十万名观众看好他们…
100, 000 on their feet for what may conceivably be…
他很快的走向擂台打一场专业拳赛
his fast walk to the ring for a professional fight.
麦斯 凯勒曼 新一代美国人有什么机会
Max Kellerman, what chance does the young American have?
他有那名字 所以今晚他在这里
He's got the name. That's why he's here tonight.
他有机会吗
Does he have the game?
他是阿波罗 奎迪的儿子
He's Apollo Creed's son he's got Rocky Balboa.
他有洛奇 巴尔博亚做他教练
in his corner.
但世界上全部的传奇人物…
But all the legends in the world…
如果他不能打谁也帮不了他
can't help him tonight if he can't fight.
问题是他能打吗
The question is can he fight?
女士们和先生们 欢迎来到英格兰利物浦…
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Goodison Park…
古迪逊公园这里…
here in Liverpool, England…
今晚最重要的体育项目
where tonight this is the main event.
十二回合制的…
12 rounds of boxing…
轻量级世界冠军锦标赛
for the light heavyweight championship of the world.
成千上万的现场观众和全世界上百万的关注…
For the thousands in attendance and the millions watching around the world…
女士们和先生们…
ladies and gentlemen…
让我们准备呐喊吧
let's get ready to rumble!
在红方穿着星星和条纹的…
In the red corner, wearing the stars and stripes…
他的职业记录是16场16胜…
his professional record, 16 fights, 16 victories…
的挑战者…
the challenger…
阿多尼斯「好莱坞」 奎迪
Adonis "Hollywood" Creed!
而在蓝方穿着黑蓝色的…
And fighting out of the blue corner, wearing black with blue…
打了36场…
with 36 fights…
28次击倒获胜…
28 KOs…
他是世界轻量级冠军…
he's the light heavyweight champion of the world…
「漂亮」 瑞奇 康兰
"Pretty" Ricky Conlan!
好了 我们上吧
Okay, let's go.
你们知道我对你们有什么要求
You known what I expect of you both.
我们在更衣室就说明了
We talked about it in the locker rooms.
我要你们时刻保护自己
I want you protect yourselve sat all times.
不能有低打 不能作弊
No low blows, no silly business.
洁身自爱 好吗 明白了吗
Keep it clean, will you? Understand?
碰拳
Touch gloves.
裤子不错啊 男孩
Nice shorts, boy.
可惜你爸比不能穿着亲自来打啊
Too bad your daddy ain't here to fight in them.
你知道什么吗 你会关上他的臭嘴的 好吗
You know what? You're gonna close his big mouth, okay?
你知道怎么做的
You know what to do.
一步 一拳 一步一步来
One step, one punch, one round at a time.
你可以的
You got this.
第一回合开始
Round one begins.
「漂亮」 瑞奇 康兰穿着黑裤子…
"Pretty" Ricky Conlan in the black trunks…
而阿多尼斯 奎迪穿着红白蓝裤子
and Adonis Creed in the red, white and blue.
康兰很明显更高…
Conlan is significantly taller…
而这会让他更容易用他的刺拳…
and thinks it will be easy to use his jab…
使年轻的奎迪陷入困境
to keep young Creed at bay.
你现在就可以看到康兰有多轻松
You can see right away how much more relaxed Conlan is.
他很有经验
He's been there before.
脚动起来
Move your leg!
把左手抬起来
Keep your left up!
这种紧张的力量可以让你一直打下去
That kind of nervous energy can wear you out as the fight goes on.
康兰左勾拳 奎迪后退
Hard left hook by Conlan. Creed backs off.
从来没打过像康兰这样的对手…
It's not easy to just jump right into the major leagues like this…
要进入到这样的大联盟可不容易…
having never fought an opponent like Conlan.
当然 像康兰这样的拳手可不多
Of course, there aren't many fighters like Conlan.
奎迪想靠近康兰 破网而出
Creed trying to get close to Conlan, against the ropes.
康兰很简单又把他们的距离拉远了
Conlan easily puts distance between them again.
康兰打出了一击重拳 重击了他的右眉角…
Confan fires a hard body punch, hits him hard with a right cross…
- 把奎迪逼到绳边 - 分开
-and backs Creed into the ropes. - Break!
裁判 不是吧
Ref, come on!
别耍花样
Keep it clean!
而他被裁判警告
And he gets a warning from the referee.
奎迪好像被那一击给唤醒了…
Creed kinds woke him up with that shot…
而康兰让他付出了代价
And Conlan really made him pay for it.
奎迪试图攻击
Creed ready to let his hands go.
奎迪没击中而马上被反击
Creed misses and gets hit in return.
- 完美的内上勾拳 - 到边上 一
-Perfect uppercut on the inside. - To the corner! One!
- 奎迪跪下来了 - 二
-Down goes Creed. - Two!
- 三 四 - 我没事
-Three! Four! - I'm good! I'm good!
- 五 六 - 我没事
-Five! Six! - I'm good!
抖身子
Shake it off!
但瑞奇 康兰已经有一个击倒了
But already a knockdown for Ricky Conlan.
- 你还好吗 你确定吗 - 我没事
-Are you okay? Are you sure? - I'm good!
开打
Fight!
康兰一轮打击后铃声响
Conlan lands a shot after the bell,
而第一回合都是瑞奇 康兰得分
and round one was all Ricky Conlan.
面对现实了吗 孩子 面对现实了吗
Real for you now, boy? Real for you now?
- 眼睛怎么样 - 有点血
-How's the eye? - Little bloody.
听着 不要慌张
All right, look. Don't get rattled.
- 我会打到他屁滚尿流的 - 下回合就上 别等了
-I'm gonna knock his ass out. - Do it in the nest round. Don't wait.
你继续像这样犯错…
You keep making mistakes like that…
我们就要用尸袋来带你走了 好吗
we're gonna pick you up with a vacuum cleaner, okay?
阿多尼斯很幸运刚那回合没多三十秒
Adonis was lucky there wasn't another 30 seconds in that round.
加油啊 你在干什么
Come on, baby. What you doing?
这是我要你做的 他会出右刺拳
Here's what I want you to do. He's gonna jab and throw the right.
当他收拳的时候出右勾拳粉碎他 好吗
When he leaves it out there, drop that right hook and smash him, okay?
保持专注
Stay focused.
那么第一回合对年轻的阿多尼斯 奎迪是一个可怕的体验
So round one was a forbidding experience for young Adonis Creed.
现在 在跟洛奇 巴尔博亚讨论之后…
And now, after a discussion with Rocky Balboa between rounds…
接下来又更多招
here comes in for more.
康兰在第一回合的结尾显示了他的力量…
Conlan showed his power witgh the uppercut at the end of round one…
回到现场开始第二回合
goes back to boxing to begin the second.
谨记
Be first!
继续压他 瑞奇
Keep the pressure on, Rick!
从逻辑上说奎迪需要找方法到康兰的长手臂内…
Logic says Cree needs to find a way to got inside of Conlan's long arms…
而且在内部产生压力
and create pressure on the inside.
来呀
Come on!
目前为止还是瑞奇 康兰占优
So far, it's still mostly Ricky Conlan.
康兰重左勾拳 上勾拳
Hard left hook for Conlan, uppercut.
- 防守啊 - 又再把奎迪逼到角落
-Keep your hands up! - Drives Creed into the corner again.
抱住他
Tie him up!
奎迪抱住他把他推开阻止了这轮攻击
Creed wraps him up and pulls turn in to stop the onslaught.
你是冠军 对吧
You the champ, right?
你是冠军
You the champ?
打给我看看啊 来呀
Show me. Come on!
奎迪击中了完美的右勾拳
There's a perfect right-hand shot by Creed!
好样的
Yeah!
漂亮
Yes!
奎迪疯了而他们在互殴
Creed misses wildly, and they are going toe-to-toe.
迅速的成为一个电话亭之战
Rapidly becomming a phone booth fight!
上啊
Go! Go!
你一拳我一拳 右手 左手 两个都屌爆了
Trading punches, right hand, left hand! Both guys landing!
这一幕太不可思议了
This is unbelievable action!
勾拳 加油
Doubt hook! Come on!
奎迪一击右重勾拳
Hard right hand by Creed.
- 你跟我一样在流血 - 回到你们的角上 快
-You bleed just like me! - Go to your corners! Come on!
你跟我一样在流血
You bleed just like me!
这什么都不是
Man! That ain't shit!
如果康兰认为他的对手很容易击败 他现在该醒醒了
He loves it! If Conlan thought he had a pushover, he knows better now!
- 他跟我一样在流血 - 你是属于这里的
-He bleed like me! - You belong in here!
他们不知道你经历了什么…
They don't know what you've been through…
而且他们也不知道我们经历了什么
and they sure don't know what we've been through.
我不想你跟他两败躯伤
I don't want you trading blows with him.
我要你保护自己
I want you to protect yourself.
保持你的距离
Keep your distance!
我要粉碎这个渣渣
I'm gonna smash this Wto bits.
现在他知道你是真材实料了
Now he knows you're for real.
你要相信你可以做到的
You gotta believe you can do it.
刚那回合对奎迪很重要
That was such a big round for Creed.
不只是在记分板上而是在心理上有很大的跃进 吉姆
Not just on the scorecards but psychologically going forward, Jim.
你唤醒了一个沉睡中的巨人
You woke up a sleeping giant.
他会使出全力来对付你的
He's gonna come after you with everything he's got.
阿多尼斯面对冠军看起来越来越自信…
Adonis, looking more and more confortabte against the champ…
似乎找到他的节奏
seems to have found his rhythm.
出去结束他
Go finish him off.
- 这已经演变成一场激战 - 一次一拳
-This has devolved into a slugfest! - One punch at a time!
加油 唐
Come on, D!
康兰想短时间内了结奎迪
Conlans trying to punish Creed at short range.
现在结束他
Finnish him now!
康兰一鼓作气的结束第三回合…
Big combination to end the third by Conlan…
而奎迪神志不清走错了角落
and Creed does not know where he is, walking to the wrong corner there.
他的手很长
His arm is long.
因为你被牵着鼻子走 唐尼
Because you're playing his game, Donnie.
要忍耐
Be patient.
一步 一拳
One step, one punch…
- 一步一步来 - 就这样
-One round at a time. - There you.
一步…
One step…
一拳…
one punch…
一步一步来
one round at a time.
12回合制第五回合…
Round five of a scheduled 12…
与早前大多数专家预计的有很大区别
and already it's a far different fight than most experts expected.
他只是个冒牌
He's just a pretender.
他很幸运可以在同一个擂台上被你打
He's lucky to be in the same ring with you hitting him.
记住这一点
Remember that.
阿多尼斯 奎恩很成功迫使瑞奇 康兰使出全力
Adonis Creed has succeed in pressuring Ricky Conlan and making him fight.
奎恩在这场拳赛充分的证明他不是好欺负的
Creed has proven plenty in this fight He's taken it, he's given it back.
但他不像一场…
But he does not look like a match…
最好同等级的世界拳赛
for the best pound-for-pound fighter in the world.
你在那里很难熬…
You're going throgh hell out there…
但你也在给他打击 我可以从他眼里看得出
but you're hurting him too. I can see it in his eyes.
你没有你想的落后那么多
You're not as far behind as you think.
短距离打刺拳 缩短距离…
Shorten that jab, shorten the distance…
到他的下面你就能揍死他了
get underneath him, and you'll be able to rip him.
你要压回他
You gotta push him back.
大多数评论家没想到奎迪可以熬这么久
Most critics didn't think Creed could make it this far.
唐尼 后退往下避开
Donnie, step under!
漂亮
Yes!
加油 瑞奇
Come on, Ricky!
有一刻奎恩控制了局势
There are moments when Creed is assertively taking over.
但马上被狠狠的反击迫使奎迪回到角落
But there's a hard counter right, drives Creed back into the corner.
就在奎恩刚有机会控制局势…
Just when it appears Creed might be taking control…
康兰近身打到他毫无反击之力
Conlan comes close to knocking him down.
施加压力 你才是控制局势的那个人
Use that pressure. You are the one that's in the driving seat.
他不是你这个等级的 好吗
He's not used to this level, all right?
双手放绳子上 深呼吸
Get 'em on the rope! Deep breath.
他速度很快
Boy's fast.
是你对你自己
Hey! It's you against you.
- 我对我自己 - 这就对了
-Me again me. - That's right.
- 他只是挡着你的路 - 明白
-He's just in your way. - Got it.
走你自己的路 加油吧
Get in out of the way! Let's go!
年轻的阿多尼斯 奎迪…
Not only is young Adonis Creed…
不只还在擂台上 他可能还可以打
still in the ring, he may be in the fight.
奎迪一击重左拳
Hard left hand by Creed.
康兰是一个压倒性的大热门…
Conlan was an overwhelmingly heavy favorite…
现在双手连续重击年轻的奎恩
pounding young Creed with right hands as you saw right there.
把一切伤害过你的拿回来
Bring back everything that's ever hurt you.
所有你的痛 包括你以前所有的东西
Al the pain you had inside, everything that held you back.
把它放在两个拳头里 我要你打到他的身体…
Put it in both fists, and I want you to drive it through his body…
我向你保证他会倒下的
and I promise you, his head will fall.
我们进入到了本能发挥作用的阶段了
We're into the part of the fight where all your instincts come into play.
大部分专家预计康兰会避免跟奎迪互殴…
Most experts expected that Conlan would avoid trading shots with Creed…
但他很乐意互殴
but he's trading willingly.
奎迪打出了重拳
Creed fires a hard body punch.
康兰麻烦了
Conlan in trouble!
左重拳打到身体
Hard left hand to the body.
冠军很难受啊 吉姆
The champ is in bad shape, Jim.
奎迪意识到他打康兰的身体
Creed realized he has a better chance of hurting Conlan.
比头有更大的机会
to the body than to the head!
- 好勾拳 - 不
-What an uppercut! - No!
而奎迪摇摇晃晃的
And Creed staggers back.
打身体
Body! Body!
打身体 彼此攻击
To the body, trading shots!
靠着他的刺拳奎迪看起来有一个很大的机会
Pawing with his jab, Creed looks to land one big shot.
脚动起来
Move your legs!
唐尼 起来
Donnie, get up!
起来 唐
Get up, D!
加油啊 宝贝
Come on, baby.
史迪奇
Stitch!
奎迪刚像个着了魔的人起来了
Creed just got up like a man possessed.
你还好吗 看着我
You okay? Look at me!
- 他刚晕倒了 - 唐尼
-He was out! - Donnie!
倒下但没晕过去
Down but not out.
康兰以为他在庆祝一个击倒…
Conlan thinks he's celebrating a knockout…
下来 他站起来了
Get down! He's getting up!
但裁判握着奎迪的拳套
but the referee is dusting Creed's gloves.
你没事
You're good.
奎迪战胜了倒数又再次行动
Creed beats the count and the action begins again.
那就是冠军的心
That's the heart of a champion.
我会告诉你他有他爸爸的心
He has his daddy's heart, I'll tell you that much.
唐尼 准备好
Donnie, be ready!
康兰又要继续 身体攻击
More work to do for Conlan. Body shot. Body dhot.
想让奎迪再次击倒
Trying to set Creed up one more time.
抱住他
Tie him up, for Christ's sake!
史迪奇给右眼护理得很好…
Stitch has done a great job over that right eye…
但现在左眼看起来像几乎闭上了
but now the left eye looks like it's almost shut.
闭上眼
Closing up.
- 洛奇 他还好吗 - 你得回到你的…
-Rock, is he okay? - You have to go back to your…
呆在那 比安卡 他没事
Stay there, Bianca, it's okay.
我没激动
I'm cool, man, I'm cool!
我没事
I'm good.
- 你没事 - 是的 好吧
-You're good? - Yeah, man, all right?
- 你确定吗 - 我没事
-You sure febout that? - I am. I'm good.
他的身体和头都承受了很多的伤害
He's taken a lot of punishment to both the body and the head.
左眼完全闭上了
Left eye completely closed.
- 我要终止比赛 - 不
-I'm gonna stop this thing. - No!
让我看看你的眼睛
Let me see the eye.
时间到了 医生来给他看看
Time! Doc, give him a look!
好了 给我看看你的眼睛
All right. Show me your eye.
给我看看你的眼睛 阿多尼斯
Show me your eye, Adonis!
有多少只手指
How many fingers?
有多少 阿多尼斯
How many, Adonis?
四只
Four.
再来
And again.
二只
Two.
时间到
Time in!
用口吸气 深呼吸
All right. Breathe through your mouth. Deep breaths, kid, deep.
你是王牌 你在占优 你会赢这场比赛的
You are up on the cards, you're winning this. You are gonna win this!
但要聪明点跟他保持距离
But just keep smart and keep away from him.
他这次会晕倒的 他这回合就不行了
He's going to sleep this time. He's going out this round.
我应该替你父亲终止这场比赛
I should've stopped the fight with your father.
我现在就终止比赛
I'm stopping this one now.
不要 好吗 让我打到最后
Don't, okay? Let me finish.
- 我要证明 - 证明什么
-I gotta prove it. - Prove what?
我不是一个错误
I'm not a mistake.
看着我
Look at me.
我从来没有机会感谢阿波罗在米奇死后帮我渡过难关
I never got a chance to thank Apollo for helping me out after Mickey died.
但那对你做的没什么可比的
But it's nothing compared to what you've done.
你教了我怎么再去战斗…
You taught me how to fight again…
而我会回家跟癌症战斗
and I'm gonna go home and I'm gonna fight this thing.
但如果我战斗我要你也要战斗
But if I fight I want you to fight, too.
我要你进到擂台…
I want you to go across this ring…
把这狗娘养的揍死 你能做到了
and knock that son of a bitch down. Can you do it?
说出来
Say it.
我会揍死那个狗娘养的
I'm gonna knock that son of a bitch down.
我知道你会的 你知道为什么吗
I know you are. You know why?
因为你是奎迪的后代而且我爱你 孩子
Because you're a Creed and I love you, kid.
- 我也爱你 - 继续吧
-I love you too. - Go on.
好了 上场吧
All right baby, let's go.
上啊 唐尼
Go get him, Donnie!
第12回合开始
Round 12 begins.
事实上场外没有一个
Virtually no one outside of.
阿多尼斯 奎迪的家人或朋友在…
Adonis Creed's family and group of friends…
会预料到他跟「漂亮」
would ever have expected to see him.
瑞奇 康兰打到12回合…
in a 12th round against "Pretty" Ricky Conlan…
互殴来到这最后的三分钟
and trading shots as they come to these last three minutes.
那是击很重的左勾拳
And there's a hard left hook upstairs.
好样的
Yeah!
每次你想说这是终结的开始…
Every time you wanna say it's die beginning of the end…
另一个人都会让你意想不到的熬过去
the other guy comes through with a shot you can't believe.
康兰一击重右拳
Hard right hand by Conlan.
加油 别发呆
Come on! Don't sit there!
他们有来有回的互殴…
They're trading shots in the kind of back and forth action…
而我们大部分人都没预想到
that most of us didn't expect to see.
奎迪被连续重拳攻击…
Creed getting hit with some hard shots…
但他自己站稳了 而且阿多尼斯反击了
but landing some of his own, and Adonis is firing back!
两个战士间的另一种较量
Another pitched battle between the two warriors.
瑞奇 结束他
Ricky, nail him!
加油啊 孩子
Come on, kid!
奎迪转身 把冠军逼到了角落
Creed spins, puts the champ in the corner!
打身体
Body!
他就像洛奇 巴尔博亚挥动身体攻击
Throwing body shots like he's Rocky Balboa!
他就像阿波罗 奎迪一样攻击上面
Going upstairs like he's Apollo Creed.
揍死他
Knock his ass out!
比赛快结束了
Closing seconds of the fight!
瑞奇
Ricky!
这才像样啊
That's what I'm talking about!
康兰倒下了
Conlan is down!
这是他职业生涯首次倒地
That is the first time in his career he's been on the canvas.
你不能在最后一回合靠铃声所救
You cannot be saved by the bell in the 12th and final round.
瑞奇 起来
Ricky, get up!
别起来
Stay down!
六
Six!
- 在利物浦激动人心的倒数 - 七 八
-Dramatic count in Liverpool. - Seven! Eight!
他必须要起来才能有机会赢这场比赛
He must get up to preserve his chance to win the fight.
- 你还好吗 - 我没事
-Are you all right? - I'm okay.
- 看着我 - 我没事
-Look at me! - I'm all right!
- 他起来了 - 什么
-He's up! - What?
铃声响起 所以康兰在最终回合活下来了
The bell sounds, so Conlan survives the 12th round!
真精彩
What a finish!
如果那回合再多三十秒我们可能就有新冠军了
If that round goes another 30 seconds, we may have a new champion.
在一个难忘的晚上的一场难忘的拳赛
An unforgettable fight on an unforgettable night!
他不再只是一个跟阿波罗 奎迪的同姓人…
He's no longer just the namesake of Apollo Creed, …
他是一个活着的化身
he's the living embodiment.
女士们和先生们 来点掌声…
Ladies and gentlemen, a round of applause…
给擂台上的这两位战士
for these two warriors in the ring!
由得分决定的胜者…
To the winner by split decision…
仍然是不败的世界冠军…
and still the undefeated champion of the world…
你做得很好 孩子
You did great, kid.
「漂亮」 瑞奇 康兰
"Pretty" Ricky Conlan!
唐尼 你是输在时间上
Donnie, you were robbed.
如果还多十秒钟…
If this fight had been 10 seconds longer…
多十秒钟…
10 seconds longer…
奎迪
Creed.
你继续努力 朋友 你是拳坛的未来
You go and get it, chum. You the future of this division.
你带着骄傲配得上这名字
You wear that name with pride.
感谢
Respect.
恭喜你 阿多尼斯 不懈的努力
Congratulations, Adonis, on a sensational effort.
我只是想感谢我的母亲 她在家里 我爱你
I just wanna thank my mom. She's at home. I love you.
虽然我知道她对我打拳很生气
Even though I know she's mad at me for doing this.
希望我会让你觉得骄傲吧
Hopefully I made her proud.
你差点让我心脏病发作了 但我很为你骄傲
You almost gave me a heart attack but I'm proud of you.
我有我的家人在
I got my family right.
没有他们就没有我在这的可能
Without them none of this would've been possible.
洛奇…
Rocky…
阿波罗 奎迪的儿子…
Apollo Creed's son…
看着你说家人
looks at you and says family.
这对你有什么意义
What does that mean to you?
这意味着我很幸运 我还能说什么 对吧
It means I'm a lucky guy. What can I say, right, kid?
他是一个真正的斗士 而且他在帮我面对新的挑战…
He's a real fighter, and he's helping me fight a new things…
所以我很感激 真的
so I appreciate it. I really do.
阿多尼斯 我知道你从没见过你父亲
Adonis, I know you never met your father.
但如果他今晚在这里 你会想对他说什么
But if he was here tonight, what would you wanna say to him?
我只是想告诉他我爱他…
I'll just tell him I love him…
而且我知道他不是故意丢下我的
and I know he didn't leave me on purpose.
还有我很骄傲能成为一个奎迪
And I'm proud to be a Creed.
谢谢 还有为你极好的表现表示祝贺 吉姆
Thanks, Adonis, and congratulations on a sensational performance. Jim.
奎迪
Creed! Creed! Creed!
来啊
Go on.
跟他们说说话
Talk to them. Go on!
观众们都热情高涨 没有一个想离开竞技场
This crowd is up on its feet. No one wants to leave the arena.
每个在这里的人都知道他们看到些很特别的东西
Everyone in here knows they've seen something special.
一场他们永不会忘的拳赛
A fight they will never forget.
瑞奇 康兰赢了比赛
Ricky Conlan wins the fight.
阿多尼斯 奎恩赢了这个晚上
Adonis Creed wins the night.
就这里
This is it?
没错
Yeah.
我只是想看看我能不能爬这些楼梯
I just wanna see if I can get up these steps.
你第一次过来是什么时候
When's the first time you came here?
我当时12岁
I was 12.
我想这是我最喜欢的地方
I think it's my favorite place.
当你登到顶端…
When you get to the top…
你会觉得你可以飞
you think you can fly.
快到了
Almost there.
你很轻松
You got this.
来吧 年轻人
Come on, young man.
让我喘口气
Just let me catch my breath.
快点 别休息 我们到顶端休息
Come on, no breaks. We rest at the top.
就一会
Just a minute.
不 这是你要求的 对吧
Nah, this is what you asked for, right?
我们走吧 一步一步来
Lets go. One step at a time.
没错
Yeah.
来吧
Come on.
一步一步来 谁告诉你的
One step at a time. Who told you that?
一个老家伙
Some old guy.
你知道我是说你 不是说我
You know I meant that for you, not for me.
我想他们又增加了几级楼梯
I think they added a few more steps.
我不知道
I don't know.
快到了
Almost there.
我来走完这最后两级
I'm gonna take these last two.
还有一级
One more step.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
好 很好
Good. Really good.
- 你还好吗 老家伙 - 没事
-You all right there, old man? - Yeah.
风景真漂亮
Nice view.
如果你注意看你可以在这到你整个人生
If you look hard enough, you can see your whole life from up here.
看起来怎么样
How does it look?
很不错 你呢
Not bad at all. And you?
很不错
Not bad at all.